<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Outside | Shital Shah</title>
    <link>https://shitalshah.github.io/categories/outside/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://shitalshah.github.io/categories/outside/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Outside</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>(C) Shital Shah. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2010 23:46:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://shitalshah.github.io/img/shitalshah.jepg</url>
      <title>Outside</title>
      <link>https://shitalshah.github.io/categories/outside/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burning Man Tips for the First Timers</title>
      <link>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/burning-man-tips-for-the-first-timers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2010 23:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/burning-man-tips-for-the-first-timers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is no substitute to reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.burningman.com/preparation/event_survival/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;official Survival Guide&lt;/a&gt; but it does leaves out many things. So instead of writing my detailed trip report I thought about all the mistakes I’d made and converting them to tips. Here it goes…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sun shelter (things that look like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rei.com/product/731380&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;REI Alcove&lt;/a&gt;) is absolutely essential if you just have a camping tent. I would however not recommend REI Alcove itself because it broke after withstanding 3 days of sandstorms. Obviously you also need &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rei.com/product/766564&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;nice camping chair&lt;/a&gt; to go with it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regular tent stacks are not very useful to secure tents on playa. I didn’t believed that and my tent almost came out in sandstorms. The correct way to secure tent in playa is using something called “&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.homedepot.com/h_d1/N-5yc1vZ1xh8/R-100323499/h_d2/ProductDisplay?langId=-1&amp;amp;storeId=10051&amp;amp;catalogId=10053&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;rebars&lt;/a&gt;”. You need 4 rebars for a regular camping tent, each 3” long and 1/2” wide. You need another 4 or 6 for sun shelter. Stores like Home Depot would cut the metal rod for you in these sizes. Of course, you will need big hammer as well to stack them (they don’t have pointy end). Finally, it’s a hazard to leave other end of these rusty metal rods open so you must stick a tennis ball or empty bottles on end of the rod that is sticking out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sandstorms!&lt;/strong&gt; In 2009 there were 3 full days of sandstorms. If you never seen one then here’s how it works: About 20-60 foot tall wall of sand that comes at you at anywhere between 10 miles to 40 miles an hour. The visibility typically drops to 5ft to 50ft and you see brownish sand everywhere around you. This can last for up to 8 hours straight. It actually looks cool and as a matter of fact I intentionally spent lots of time inside sandstorm taking photos (note: Many SLRs are not dust proof). Even on severe storm days almost everyone continued their activities as if it was normal weather. But they were prepared. Here’s what you need to be prepared:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to have sun glasses with minimum open space around lenses. I had &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rei.com/product/766496&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tifosi Ventoux&lt;/a&gt; and they worked kind of OK. A &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rei.com/search?cat=8000&amp;amp;cat=4500069&amp;amp;cat=4500650&amp;amp;hist=cat%2C4500069%3ASunglasses^cat%2C4500650%3ASunglass+Retainers&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;retainer&lt;/a&gt; is also essential not to loose them (remember there are no shops to buy extra pair).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mask for the nose and mouth. I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.buffwear.com/catalog/index.php?cPath=1_5&amp;amp;sort=2a&amp;amp;max=1000000&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Buff bandana&lt;/a&gt; so I can pull it up all the way to sunglasses. Next time I would also be using &lt;a href=&#34;http://solutions.3m.com/wps/portal/3M/en_US/Health/Safety/Products/Catalog/?PC_7_RJH9U5230GE3E02LES9MG812H2_nid=XKJJ787RSQbeF3RH7CD92Ngl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rei.com/product/769766&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.icanbreathe.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; mask so I can be absolutely worry free about staying longer out in dust storms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hat with cord and visor. This will allow you to walk heads down while visor protects your face. I used &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sundayafternoons.com/store/adventure-hats.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this hat&lt;/a&gt; and it’s absolutely the best hat I’ve ever owned. Added advantage of this hat is that it’s veil can be put in the direction of wind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a first timer I found that 4 nights provides a very good breadth and depth for the experience. The reason it’s perfect is because you have to carry less food and water, not worry too much about getting shower and you still get to see nearly everything that’s out there. I would strongly recommend against staying &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; than 3 nights.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a stop at Reno at least for a night before heading towards Black Rock City. Besides mini-Las Vegas style environment, you can also visit REI, Walmart and Walgreens to get the gear, water, grocery and so on. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.peppermillreno.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pepermill Resort&lt;/a&gt; is where I stayed overnight because it’s cheapest awesome hotel in Reno.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A compass is very useful to have to get on the right street when coming back in the night far away from playa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have 3-season camping tent you are probably in trouble. These tents usually have mesh in the walls for ventilation and they have rain fly to protect against rain. This arrangement however is pretty useless to protect against sandstorms. On a typical stormy day I would get about half inch layer of sand inside my 3 season tent and I had to spend an hour every night cleaning things up. Make sure you have duct tapes and things to cover up. Everything outside tent should be tied to rebars so it doesn’t fly away with storms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weather at burning man is 110F+. It’s normally not possible to sleep inside the tent after 10 AM. It’s not unusual to stay up until 3 AM. Nights are cold and you will need a fleece jacket. I’d 30 degree rated &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rei.com/product/760252&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;bag&lt;/a&gt; which was bit warmer but worked fine. BTW, try to bring sleeping bag liner to avoid it getting sweaty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a first timer it might be hard to understand culture of gifts. For example, someone I don’t know at all would give me something and I would be confused if I should really take it. This can spoil the experience for the giver and the taker. Here’s how it works: If someone gives you a gift, take it with a smile without hesitation and give them a gift in return. It’s that simple. The only thing to remember is to bring bunch of gifts that you can easily carry around. Here are some of the examples of gifts: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.123stickers.com/index.asp?PageAction=Custom&amp;amp;ID=68&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Custom stickers&lt;/a&gt; with your favorite quotes, necklaces, bead jewelry, &lt;a href=&#34;http://glowproducts.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;things that glows&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/s/qid=1282811182/ref=sr_nr_seeall_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;keywords=zimbabwe%20dollars&amp;amp;rh=i%3Aaps%2Ck%3Azimbabwe%20dollars%2Ci%3Amisc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Trillion Dollars Notes&lt;/a&gt;, candies, custom printed postcards and so on. A single major mistake first timers make is not to bring gifts to give away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bicycles would be your savior. If you can’t bring from home then rent or steal from Reno. BRC is really huge and you would be lucky if you could walk just one street a day. Most events that I was interested usually were many miles apart and it’s impossible to make it on time without bicycle. Besides you really don’t want to get tired after walking 10 miles just to attend couple of events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As soon as you enter gate you will be handed a map and booklet of events. The map is easy to understand because of it’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://earth.burningman.com/brc/2009/map/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;semi-circle streets&lt;/a&gt;. Any location is specified by using hand of clock and name of the street. The 6 o’clock is the center while 2 o’clock and 10 o’clock are two ends of semi-circle. The street names are different every year depending on the theme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is NO assigned camping sites at Burning Man (except for theme camps). Normally all except outer two streets are occupied within first couple of days. When I arrived on Wednesday evening I decided to keep as much distance from outer road as possible because that’s where all the cars keep passing by. But I did not wanted to be too inside because the view of vast playa on the outer street is awesome. I also wanted to stay in middle so distance to get on any side is minimized. Always consider if your neighbors have enough space around their tent to put picnic table or chairs or grills or another car. The best space I found on Wednesday night was at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gigapan.org/gigapans/34311/snapshots/161246/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;7:15 and Kinship&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If someone asks you “which camp are you in?” then that usually means “what is the name of your camp?”. You can consult with your neighbor to decide on some name for group camp and put on the sign. You can also tell the location such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gigapan.org/gigapans/34311/snapshots/161246/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;7:15 &amp;amp; Kinship&lt;/a&gt; like other first timers do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The iPhone &amp;amp; AT&amp;amp;T did worked with full 4 bars at Black Rock City in 2009. It’s really really a good choice to turn it off and resist temptation to tweet/facebook for your entire stay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here’s one of the most disgusting part of my Burning Man experience: The place I choose to camp was up-winds in the path of potty patties. That means every time wind blew even a little it would smell really really bad. It was horrible. Fortunately I came to my tent only to sleep when smell was gone. It’s really worth to make sure you avoid such smelly spaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t wear jeans at Burning Man! Many places that do not allow jeans believe that they are too “casual” for them but at Burning Man you don’t want to wear jeans because they would be too “formal”! I wore my normal jeans on first night and felt so out of place and formal that it was embarrassing. If you must wear jeans then take your old jeans, paint them or tear them or whatever. Shorts are semi-casual options at Burning Man.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The list of events at Burning Man is overwhelming. You do not have to go crazy to attend as many events as possible and it’s best to chose no more than 3 events per day to attend. It’s good idea to reserve one day just sit back at your tent and look at vast playa in mild warm wind :).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cooking at Burning Man can get tricky because of sandstorms. I’d bought my camping stove which didn’t work out in storms. Fortunately more prepared folks did cooking in their camps and gave away lots of free food. I’d also bought some non-perishable stuff like bananas, milk powder, Sahale snacks, bars, chips and so on. One last option for food is to go back to town via bus or car but that might ruin your experience. Fortunately I did not had that option because I didn’t had car and I never found the bus. One good outcome was that I lost few pounds! Next time I might just buy or rent a grill because it work better in dust storms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I estimated 1.5 gallon of water per day per person and it worked out well for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can meet and greet your neighbors without feeling awkward. When you cook meal, offer some to them. Always have at least two gifts to give away to your two neighbors while departing. Example of gifts are some sketch you made while at Burning Man or other art work or a poem or your favorite book or some photo you took.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes, you do need &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rei.com/product/758050&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;kitchen sink&lt;/a&gt;! You will need it to brush teeth, wash hands etc. It’s not OK to spill water with soap on playa floor but if your sink is small and soap biodegradable then you would be ok to collect water in it and then go to outer street to flung it away&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most people do not shower at Burning Man (or so I think). There are few elaborate large camps that set up showers and some even offer them to others as well. But in general, don’t expect showers. Alternative is wet towel to wipe off of your body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many camps on inner circle serves free drinks to anyone who wants but you need to bring your own cup. It helps a lot if you have a cup with lid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a place everybody refers to as “The Temple”. It’s located beyond The Man and many first timers would even miss it because they usually don’t go beyond The Man (it’s a LONG walk too). The Temple is truly sacred in many aspects without being connected to even the concept of religion. It’s humbling and even moving to spend a day at the temple. The Temple burns on next day after The Man burns and more spectacularly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Burning Man usually has 35,000+ people which causes 2 to 4 hours of traffic jams while leaving. While it’s fun to see the parade of every RV ever made, the time with least traffic to leave Burning Man is on Saturday night after The Man burns. But the flip side is that you will miss even more spectacular burn of The Temple which is on Sunday night. Another flip side of leaving on Saturday night is that you run huge risk of falling sleep while driving. When I left on Saturday night I saw at least 3 accidents on the way and so I decided to just pull over and sleep anyway. For my next time, I would be leaving on Monday late afternoon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally here are &lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/sytelus1/BurningMan2009#5509703293720242962&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;pictures from my trip&lt;/a&gt; which hopefully would give some idea about what to expect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mountain Weather in Washington</title>
      <link>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/mountain-weather-in-washington/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2010 06:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/mountain-weather-in-washington/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Usual weather websites do not give you the forecast at a point but rather around some town/city which renders them pretty useless for mountains. Here are the collected links for mountain weather forecasts for Washington:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=46.77557504115353&amp;amp;lon=-121.74479126930237&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mount Rainier at Paradise Visitor Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=46.835477098178494&amp;amp;lon=-121.73139095306396&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mount Rainier at Camp Muir&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=48.46654767913529&amp;amp;lon=-121.05972290039062&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;North Cascades NP – Sahale Arm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=48.4748&amp;amp;lon=-121.0735&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;North Cascades NP – Sahale Arm TH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=48.720357602590724&amp;amp;lon=-120.6697940826416&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;north Cascades NP – Windy Pass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=48.0702&amp;amp;lon=-121.8147&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;North Cascades NP – Mount Pilchuck TH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=46.240651955001695&amp;amp;lon=-122.14599609375&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mount St Helens – Windy Ridge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=46.2499&amp;amp;lon=-122.1362&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mount St Helens – Windy Ridge TH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=48.84693994263992&amp;amp;lon=-121.69255256652832&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mount Baker – Artist Point&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=48.874651&amp;amp;lon=121.855215&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mount Baker – Skyline Divide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=-48.8463&amp;amp;lon=-121.6927&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mount Baker – Ptarmigan Ridge TH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=47.48385887160761&amp;amp;lon=-120.78180313110352&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Enchantments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=47.91870051188839&amp;amp;lon=-123.38238716125488&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Olympics – Hurricane Ridge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=47.941963086450755&amp;amp;lon=-124.65096473693847&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Olympics – Hole in the Wall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=47.8278&amp;amp;lon=-123.0408&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Olympics – Mamot Pass TH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=45.672363557944365&amp;amp;lon=-123.93608093261719&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Oregon Coast – Nehalem Bay State Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=45.330366510894535&amp;amp;lon=-121.70937538146973&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mount Hood – Timberline Lodge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=45.426407377512774&amp;amp;lon=-121.72164916992188&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mount Hood – Vista Ridge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=47.50653361720931&amp;amp;lon=-121.739501953125&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Snoqualmie Pass Corridor – Mount Si&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=47.42367407957422&amp;amp;lon=-121.49333953857422&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Snoqualmie Pass Corridor – Granite Mountain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=47.45954949060109&amp;amp;lon=-121.4668607711792&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Snoqualmie Pass Corridor – Chair Peak/Snow Lake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=47.4174&amp;amp;lon=-120.9361&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Salmon La Sac – Iron Peak TH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.weather.gov/MapClick.php?lat=47.4292&amp;amp;lon=-120.9377&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Esmeralda Basin TH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snoqualmie Falls Hike Analysis</title>
      <link>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/snoqualmie-falls-hike-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 09:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/snoqualmie-falls-hike-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today was perhaps my 32nd hike at Snoqualmie Falls. I&amp;rsquo;ve adopted this trail as my daily hike routine. Today I brought my new Garmin Oregon 400t GPS with me and recorded the track. Fortunately there is a website (although not that good) called MotionBased which can slice and dice and analyze this track data and tell you lot of cool things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the MotionBased&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://trail.motionbased.com/trail/invitation/dashboard.mb?episodePk.pkValue=7658501&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;analysis of Snoqualmie Falls hike&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few interesting things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a 1.4 miles hike with 475 ft elevation gain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hike takes about 35 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ascent and descent speeds as well as times are roughly same (note that I do not made any stops except at ends of the trail).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My speed while ascending is 2.4 mph and vertical speed is 14 ft/min or 840 ft/hr. Not too bad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This hike has average grade of 16%. This is just 1% more than max allowed by typical gym treadmills. At steepest point the trail is 30% grade while about the &amp;ldquo;safe&amp;rdquo; max limit on typical maintained trails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using my watch which can measure elevation I thought that was 300ft elevation hike. Obviously my watch can easily be 100ft off. Here&amp;rsquo;s the elevation profile of this hike:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://shitalshah.github.io/images/posts/2009/02/SnoqualmieHikeProfile.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://shitalshah.github.io/images/posts/2009/02/SnoqualmieHikeProfile.png&#34; alt=&#34;SnoqualmieHikeProfile&#34; width=&#34;340&#34; height=&#34;227&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-721&#34; srcset=&#34;http://shitalshah.com/ShitalShahWP/wp-content/uploads/2009/02/SnoqualmieHikeProfile.png 340w, http://shitalshah.com/ShitalShahWP/wp-content/uploads/2009/02/SnoqualmieHikeProfile-300x200.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 340px) 100vw, 340px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the best time to hike Zion Narrows?</title>
      <link>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/what-is-the-best-time-to-hike-zion-narrows/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2009 12:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/what-is-the-best-time-to-hike-zion-narrows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I LOVE slot canyons and Zion Narrows hike is something on my To-do for very long time since I saw it in a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.netflix.com/WiPlayer?movieid=60029430&amp;amp;trkid=222336&amp;amp;lnkctr=srchrd-sr&amp;amp;strkid=2061597409_0_0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;documentary&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.netflix.com/Movie/Zion_Canyon_Treasure_of_the_Gods_IMAX/60000565?trkid=222336&amp;amp;lnkctr=srchrd-sr&amp;amp;strkid=1473599445_0_0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;IMAX&lt;/a&gt;. So when I saw this deal from Southwest about 50% off on all travels my first thought was to book tickets to Las Vegas (nearest to Zion) or SLC. Due to restriction on this deal the travel needs to be completed by May 31st.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the question: Is last week of May the best time to do Zion Narrows? I&amp;rsquo;ve fanatically looked for answer all over and here&amp;rsquo;s the summary. Disclaimer: that I haven&amp;rsquo;t been there so all these research comes from web, not my experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My criteria for &amp;ldquo;best time&amp;rdquo; is fairly simple:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid wearing dry/wet suit to do this hike&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid wading in 1ft of water for miles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pleasant 70s temperature that allows good other hikes like Angel&amp;rsquo;s Landing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several websites have various opinions on &amp;ldquo;best time&amp;rdquo;. A &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zionadventures.com/best_seasons_to_hike_the_narrows.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;top Google hit&lt;/a&gt; puts up a table indicating May, June and Septembers are the best. This is way too fuzzy answer because early May is actually as worse as April and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t tell you different late May really is compared to late June. Yes, there is a big difference!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, other websites gets more specific and tells you late June and late September is the best time. We are getting closer to a specific answer but still no data points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lot of searching I finally hit the pot of gold:&lt;a href=&#34;http://waterdata.usgs.gov/ut/nwis/dv?cb_00060=on&amp;amp;cb_00065=on&amp;amp;format=gif_default&amp;amp;begin_date=2008-01-01&amp;amp;end_date=2009-01-01&amp;amp;site_no=09405500&amp;amp;referred_module=sw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;USGA Water Data&lt;/a&gt;! This website has exact numbers for CFS (cubic foot per second) and gage height data for each day all the way back to 1988. The rules are quite simple: anything below 50 CFS is easy and 250 FS is too much. The USGA has done fantastic job in presenting this data on website. For example, here you can see CFS levels for 2008:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://shitalshah.github.io/images/posts/2009/01/NorthForkVirginRiverDischarge.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://shitalshah.github.io/images/posts/2009/01/NorthForkVirginRiverDischarge.png&#34; alt=&#34;NorthForkVirginRiverDischarge&#34; width=&#34;576&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-733&#34; srcset=&#34;http://shitalshah.com/ShitalShahWP/wp-content/uploads/2009/01/NorthForkVirginRiverDischarge.png 576w, http://shitalshah.com/ShitalShahWP/wp-content/uploads/2009/01/NorthForkVirginRiverDischarge-300x200.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 576px) 100vw, 576px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can see late May is not all that good but it is rapidly getting better over entire June although it takes all of the June before we get 40 CFS. This means late June is pretty good time to go but difference between early June and late June is almost two fold! Then notice all those spikes in early July. My guess is those are flash floods or thunderstorms. On other hand look how stable mid-end September is! We get 30 CFS almost all month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://shitalshah.github.io/images/posts/2009/01/NorthForkVirginRiverGageHeight.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://shitalshah.github.io/images/posts/2009/01/NorthForkVirginRiverGageHeight.png&#34; alt=&#34;NorthForkVirginRiverGageHeight&#34; width=&#34;576&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-732&#34; srcset=&#34;http://shitalshah.com/ShitalShahWP/wp-content/uploads/2009/01/NorthForkVirginRiverGageHeight.png 576w, http://shitalshah.com/ShitalShahWP/wp-content/uploads/2009/01/NorthForkVirginRiverGageHeight-300x200.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 576px) 100vw, 576px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we are looking at about foot of water at May end and about quarter of that in mid-end September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise you can go through charts for may years back. It obviously varies from year to year. For example, year 2007 had very low stable CFS at end of May unlike rapidly decreasing high levels of 2008.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past few years worth of charts that I checked &lt;strong&gt;one theme emerges: mid to end September has most stable and low CFS!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how about temperatures? Here&amp;rsquo;s where &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wunderground.com/NORMS/DisplayNORMS.asp?AirportCode=KCDC&amp;amp;SafeCityName=Zion_National_Park&amp;amp;StateCode=UT&amp;amp;Units=none&amp;amp;IATA=CDC&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Weather Underground&amp;rsquo;s seasonal average feature&lt;/a&gt; helps! Here is the seasonal averages weather graph for Zion National Park:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://shitalshah.github.io/images/posts/2009/01/NorthForkVirginRiverWeather.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://shitalshah.github.io/images/posts/2009/01/NorthForkVirginRiverWeather.png&#34; alt=&#34;NorthForkVirginRiverWeather&#34; width=&#34;462&#34; height=&#34;687&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-731&#34; srcset=&#34;http://shitalshah.com/ShitalShahWP/wp-content/uploads/2009/01/NorthForkVirginRiverWeather.png 462w, http://shitalshah.com/ShitalShahWP/wp-content/uploads/2009/01/NorthForkVirginRiverWeather-201x300.png 201w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 462px) 100vw, 462px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the temperature in mid-September is pleasant 70s just like in June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So there you have it! Mid September to September end (2nd and 3rd weeks of September) is the best time to go to Zion National Park and Narrows. That&amp;rsquo;s when you are most likely to get stable low water levels.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mount Si - Take #2</title>
      <link>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/mount-si-take-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2009 02:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/mount-si-take-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I tried Mount Si hike again and returned back before I saw &amp;ldquo;Snag Flats&amp;rdquo;, second time. Snag Flats are supposed to somewhere between 1300&amp;rsquo; to 1500&amp;rsquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s relatively small hike that you can do in 2-3 hours (full hike to summit of Mount Si is a long 8 hour 3200&amp;rsquo; climb). Today because of heavily packed wet snow it was extremely slippery. Many people even had crampons on. People who did not had any &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ems.com/catalog/subcategory_simple.jsp?FOLDER%3C%3Efolder_id=2534374302879862&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;traction devices&lt;/a&gt; (like me) had very hard time to go up on slippery trail and even harder time to come down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would not do this trail without wearing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rei.com/product/774966&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kahtoola Microspikes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last time I&amp;rsquo;d to turn back at1250&amp;rsquo; because I&amp;rsquo;d started too late and it was getting dark. Today I got up to 1440&amp;rsquo; but still saw no sign of so called snag flats or a view point where Mailbox peak and Mt Rainier can be seen. But then I suddenly realized that I&amp;rsquo;d forgotten my camera on the trail during last water break! So I went down to look for it but didn&amp;rsquo;t found it. I finally got down in parking lot and walked there for quite sometime looking for any lost &amp;amp; found places (&lt;a href=&#34;http://maps.google.com/maps/ms?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;msa=0&amp;amp;msid=104533212117189621673.00044d8c694b6da7eb931&amp;amp;ll=47.496618,-121.732464&amp;amp;spn=0.031315,0.090637&amp;amp;t=p&amp;amp;z=14&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mount Si trailhead&lt;/a&gt; has HUGE parking lot and somehow there are always dozen cars there). Several people were coming down or going up but no one had seen it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then an amazing thing happened. Just when I was driving out the parking lot and I was almost out, I decided to stop for a minute and put up a sticky note. And I suddenly saw 3 guys coming down and they had &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kodak.com/eknec/PageQuerier.jhtml?pq-path=11592&amp;amp;pq-locale=en_US&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my camera&lt;/a&gt;! It was just a matter of few seconds and I would have left. Thank you strangers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: Those 3 guys mentioned that they were going to return it to ranger station. So next time if you loose something always check with ranger station or forest service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates - Spring 2005</title>
      <link>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/updates-spring-2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2005 18:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/updates-spring-2005/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I would be writing all New York City related stuff at &lt;a href=&#34;http://nyc.metblogs.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Metblogs&lt;/a&gt; rather then my own blog. This makes sense because lot of people who aren&amp;rsquo;t in this region doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to get those NYC stories. On the other hand, my NYC related writing will now reach to much larger audience. Check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?q=site:nyc.metblogs.com+%22shital+shah%22&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;lr=&amp;amp;c2coff=1&amp;amp;safe=off&amp;amp;filter=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;some of my entries there&lt;/a&gt; about cool New York events, restaurants and such stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other site news, you might have noticed new skin and more FireFox friendly design. I also decided to give away the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sytelus/SyFastPage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;engine that my website runs on&lt;/a&gt; (C# code I wrote almost 4 years ago) along with entire &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sytelus/ShitalShahWebV3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;source code for this website&lt;/a&gt; (thats in VB.Net just for fun). Nothing special but main highlights of the engine is that it accepts raw HTML file as the base template and embeds your dynamic ASP.Net WebForm content inside that HTML. It also provides navigation control which runs off of XHTML templates and XML.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like my free utilities, don&amp;rsquo;t forget to check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://shitalshah.github.io/p/category/software/&#34;&gt;massive updates in my Software section&lt;/a&gt;. It has now many more of my programs and utilities that I kept it to myself. Specifically, the one called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sytelus/BrowserHistoryAnalyzer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Browser History Analyzer&lt;/a&gt; analyses your IE history (support for FireFox coming soon), builds MS Access database and gives you tons of amusing info about your browsing habits such has the queries you fired on search engine, how do you refine your keywords progressively, how much time you usually spend on a page, how much time you spend on browsing and so on. Whilte still in development, it also features extensible architecture to let you make your own plugins. I&amp;rsquo;ve also put the link for article I wrote for CodeProject about &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sytelus/WinProgressDialog&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;how to show Explorer&amp;rsquo;s progress dialog in your apps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally some &lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/photos/111712720654017421562/albums/5987178406068558081&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Alaska trip photos&lt;/a&gt; also have been added. Yenjoy :).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Alaska Trip Photos (March 2004)</title>
      <link>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/our-alaska-trip-photos-march-2004/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2004 17:57:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/our-alaska-trip-photos-march-2004/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are our &lt;a href=&#34;https://picasaweb.google.com/111712720654017421562/AlaskaTripMarch2004?authuser=0&amp;amp;feat=directlink&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;March 2004 Alaska trip photos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess&amp;nbsp;early March&amp;nbsp;is among the best time to visit Alaska (thanks to my wife for figuring out fantastic itinerary)&amp;nbsp;because you are still just in time to catch views of&amp;nbsp;Aurora Boriales and there is so much festivities going on.&amp;nbsp;We had our Yup&amp;rsquo;ik wedding ceremony at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chenahotsprings.com/icehotel.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ice Hotel at Chena Hotsprings&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;which is a hotel made of only ice with colorful lights shining through. Taking a dip in natural hot&amp;nbsp;sulfur rich springs in below freezing temperatures with Aurora Borealis&amp;nbsp;passing over head&amp;nbsp;could certainly bring you one of the most memorable times even if its not your wedding ceremony&amp;nbsp;night ;).&amp;nbsp;We&amp;nbsp;also attended the start of the world famous &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iditarod.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Iditarod Sleddog Race&lt;/a&gt; in&amp;nbsp; Anchorage,&amp;nbsp;went to&amp;nbsp;the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.furrondy.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fur Rendezvous&lt;/a&gt; (a big festival in Anchorage were furs and various Alaskan crafts are bought, sold, and traded),&amp;nbsp; saw the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.icealaska.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;World Ice Carving Championship&lt;/a&gt; in Fairbanks&amp;nbsp;- a definite must see to believe these finely detailed&amp;nbsp;sculpteurs carved out of ice, attended &lt;a href=&#34;http://henkbinnendijk.tripod.com/fairbanks/id16.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chatanika Days&lt;/a&gt; (a festival in Chatanika where a outhouse, snowmobile, and other races are held), and visited &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ci.whittier.ak.us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Whittier&lt;/a&gt;, the strangest town in Alaska.&amp;nbsp; We&amp;nbsp;also paid a visit to capitol &amp;ldquo;city&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.juneau.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Juneau&lt;/a&gt; which is incredibly beautiful from &amp;ldquo;Lower 48&amp;rdquo; standards but not as desirable places to live from Alaskan standards :).&amp;nbsp; We also camped in 4 feet of snow overnight near&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nps.gov/dena/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Denali National Park&lt;/a&gt;, home of Denali/Mt. McKinley Mountain, the tallest mountain in North America. All that besides having lots of fun :).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autumn Fall Foliage 2004</title>
      <link>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/autumn-fall-foliage-2004/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2004 04:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/autumn-fall-foliage-2004/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are reading this and haven&amp;rsquo;t been out there, well, you already missed the biggest blast of colors in Adirondacks (NY). On &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foliagenetwork.com/reports/northeast_us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;US east coast&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.state.me.us/doc/foliage/report/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Maine&lt;/a&gt; and an odd little dot in the heart of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adirondacks.com/fallreport.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Adirondacks&lt;/a&gt; are two places where the amazing fall colors appears first. Last year, just by pure fortune, &lt;a href=&#34;https://shitalshah.github.io/p/autumn-fall-foliage-long-drives-2003/&#34;&gt;I was in Adirondacks&lt;/a&gt; and in one of the first mornings I saw a sudden blast of color everywhere in the region. So we took the flight over 46 tall mountains (and the countless small ones) that makes up this amazingly beautiful area. The aerial views we saw from the small plane flying low were definitely the best fall foliage view I’ve ever seen (and for the record, I’d been &lt;a href=&#34;https://shitalshah.github.io/p/autumn-fall-foliage-long-drives-2002/&#34;&gt;out&lt;/a&gt; quite &lt;a href=&#34;https://picasaweb.google.com/111712720654017421562/AutumnFallFoliageLongDrives&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a lot&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, last weekend was the day when colors had peaked again at Adirondacks and after a week of blazing show that nature had put there, the area is now past peak (along with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foliage-vermont.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Vermont&lt;/a&gt; and much of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newhampshire.com/foliage/index.cfm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;New Hampshire&lt;/a&gt; – which is often compared with China for the best in fall foliage in entire world because of the diversity of trees). But if you plan well, you can still chase the fall foliage on the East coast for this entire month and enjoy the blazing colors in truly awesome settings! After some researching in to my collection of links and reviewing fall foliage reports from various states, I&amp;rsquo;ve prepared &lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B6Yo9hEhJ1ZnVlRHVXpDQS1VWTQ/edit?usp=sharing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this Excel sheet&lt;/a&gt; for the approximate times for fall foliage peak colors. So go out and have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autumn Fall Foliage Long Drives 2003</title>
      <link>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/autumn-fall-foliage-long-drives-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2003 04:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/autumn-fall-foliage-long-drives-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s cool to be in mountains when fall is just still arriving and you are among the first to feel it. This year my First Of Autumn hikes happened in Adirondacks. This area in upper state New York is probably among the most scenic part on East Coast. You got choice of 46 high peaks to climb (a High Peak is a mountain taller then 4000 ft) apart from countless small mountains and hills, several small and huge lakes to canoe and kayak or just relax on cruise, quite a few waterfalls and quint towns. The best part is you can even take small plane like Cessna 152 and fly over those mountains covered with fresh yellow, red, violet colors. It&amp;rsquo;s probably some of the most scenic experience you can ever have in this part of the country. But behold! Fall is just beginning. The next best thing to do is probably long drives on colorful lonely snaky roads passing through mountains, valleys and lakes. But.. where would you go? Here&amp;rsquo;s some of the best picks for autumn fall foliage road trips!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Citysearch has &lt;a href=&#34;http://local.msn.com/special/archive/travel_fall.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;their picks of top 10 fall foliage spots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://gorp.away.com/gorp/features/fall/fall_00.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GORP&amp;rsquo;s Autumn kickoff&lt;/a&gt;. They have the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gorp.away.com/gorp/activity/rv.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;great sets of scenic driving routes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.escortedfallfoliagetours.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;commercial fall tours site&lt;/a&gt; but they have good &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.escortedfallfoliagetours.com/adventure/adventure.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;adventure section&lt;/a&gt; and you can &amp;ldquo;steal&amp;rdquo; some of their iteneries 🙂&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;America&amp;rsquo;s Best also have &lt;a href=&#34;http://americasbestonline.com/fall.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;small list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are in New Jersey, pick your road trip from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.state.nj.us/travel/driving_tours_fall/falltours.shtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this great routes through out NJ&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last thing: How would you know when and where it&amp;rsquo;s peak of fall colors? There are 3 sites which can tell you when it&amp;rsquo;s time to go: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foliagenetwork.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Foliage Network&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fs.fed.us/news/fallcolors/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;USDA Forest Services&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.travelnotes.org/Travel/sep16.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this other site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Awesome Destinations</title>
      <link>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/awesome-destinations-and-times-to-visit-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2003 06:18:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/awesome-destinations-and-times-to-visit-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently went to Sierra Club&amp;rsquo;s meeting/presentation on California&amp;rsquo;s Route 1. This road trip certainly seems to be the queen of all. The presenter been touring this route every couple of years since last 3 decades and had some really awesome photographs - some taken in different seasons and time of the days and some even different decades! Here are some tips from the guru himself: The road trip to CA1 can be done any month, never let weather stop you. Still if you are too picky, in summer (through September) it&amp;rsquo;s kind of hot. From December to March is good time except that El-Nino may strike the Pacific coast and parts of CA1 suddenly merges in to ocean, yet Feb-March is the best time. This is also the time when you can see lots of white whales in the ocean floating around while watching sunset in Pacific Ocean. The good place to stay overnight on this route is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raggedpointinn.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ragged Point Inn&lt;/a&gt;. You might want to frequently take exists in between, specifically for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hearstcastle.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;San Simeon Castle&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s good idea to stay around this gorgeous huge architecture (they have even special tour for just bathrooms among others!). To stay around this building is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sspines.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;San Simeon Pines&lt;/a&gt; is a good resort. The route is 90 miles long and totally worth an entire day trip. While in presentation, I also stumbled upon list of really gorgeous places to visit in United States. They are special because they have specific times when you should be there. Also they are very diverse (from flower covered moutains to canyons in Utah!). If you get a chance, don&amp;rsquo;t even think about missing out on them. I certainly won&amp;rsquo;t :). Here&amp;rsquo;s my filtered list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bryce Canyon National Park, &lt;strong&gt;Utah&lt;/strong&gt; Canyon valleys partially gets covered in snow. Not for faint hearted.Best Time: &lt;strong&gt;Jan/Feb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cottonwood Lake, &lt;strong&gt;Alaska&lt;/strong&gt; Clear waters and ice formations in lake like a huge starfish from end to endBest Time: &lt;strong&gt;Feb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glenn Canyon National Recreation Area, &lt;strong&gt;Arizona&lt;/strong&gt; Best Time: &lt;strong&gt;Feb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tehachapi Mountains, &lt;strong&gt;California&lt;/strong&gt; Absolute gorgeous mountains completely covered with flowers. Yes, just like you had dreamed once :). Best Time: &lt;strong&gt;April&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Isla Espirita Santo, Sea of Cortes, &lt;strong&gt;Maxico&lt;/strong&gt; urrr&amp;hellip; this one is non-US.Best Time: &lt;strong&gt;May&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Painted Hills, &lt;strong&gt;Oregon&lt;/strong&gt; yes, hills that actually looks like someone painted them outBest Time: &lt;strong&gt;May&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elives Chasm, Grand Canyon National Park, &lt;strong&gt;Arizona&lt;/strong&gt; Best Time: &lt;strong&gt;June&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moraine Lake, Banff National Park, &lt;strong&gt;Alberta&lt;/strong&gt; Best Time: &lt;strong&gt;Aug&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cohutta Wilderness Area, &lt;strong&gt;Georgia&lt;/strong&gt; Best Time: &lt;strong&gt;Sep&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kennebec River, &lt;strong&gt;Main&lt;/strong&gt; Best Time: &lt;strong&gt;Oct&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Snake River, &lt;strong&gt;Wyoming&lt;/strong&gt; Best Time: &lt;strong&gt;Nov&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yosemite Falls, Yosemite National Park, &lt;strong&gt;California&lt;/strong&gt; Best Time: &lt;strong&gt;Nov&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talkeetna Mountains, &lt;strong&gt;Alaska&lt;/strong&gt; A special place where you can see Aurora Borealis! Best Time: &lt;strong&gt;Nov&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;West Indian Manatees, &lt;strong&gt;Florida&lt;/strong&gt; Best Time: &lt;strong&gt;Dec&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Owens Valley near Laws, &lt;strong&gt;California&lt;/strong&gt; Best Time: &lt;strong&gt;Dec/Jan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weddell Sea, &lt;strong&gt;Antarctica&lt;/strong&gt; urrrr&amp;hellip; this is non-US, again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cannon Beach, Ecola State Park, &lt;strong&gt;Oregon&lt;/strong&gt; Best Time: &lt;strong&gt;Dec/Jan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Visit To The Temple</title>
      <link>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/iskon-temple-west-virginia-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2003 08:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/iskon-temple-west-virginia-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d to just help my neighbour to find her run-away cat. Now a last blogbit&amp;hellip; before I really really go to bed! This Labor Day weekend I was thinking about spending 3 days in programming few stuff I&amp;rsquo;d planned but such things just can&amp;rsquo;t happen. Suddenly a plan came around out of nowhere for 12+ hours of road trip to West Virginia and a visit to an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iskcon.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ISKCON&lt;/a&gt; temple. Submitting to spontaneous weird idea seems to be my weakness. This one was weird because, well, who can think of visiting an ISKCON temple out of nowhere? While I&amp;rsquo;m not affiliated to ISKCON (or for that matter any religious organization whatsoever), I was curious about them anyway (watching Hare Krishna group dancing on Leicester Square in London is very cool) and so I joined my gang. This indeed turned out to be great road trip. We almost started at sun rise, passed through valleys and mountains covered with mist and made few stops. The temple located on the mountain top in hilly state of West Virginia has some good views. We also realized that day was little special being the last day of a festival called Paryushan from Jain religion and first day of another festival Ganesh Chaturthi and the last day when the temple remains open until 8 PM and a day when free feast is served and of course, it was the last day of summer. As if all these coincidences weren&amp;rsquo;t enough, I ran in to one of my classmates in the temple who had left his job to be a full time ISKCON person serving as deputy director of a charity hospital (it&amp;rsquo;s amazing how I keep meeting my classmates by coincidences. Last time I met one in a strip club, this time it was in a temple! And we always say this first to each other: &amp;ldquo;what the hack you doing here?&amp;rdquo;). We also took the tour of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.palaceofgold.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Palace Of Gold&lt;/a&gt; which is the memorial built for the founder of ISKCON. It&amp;rsquo;s funny though to build a memorial buried under gold for a person who probably spent his entire life fighting against materialistic world and achieving nirvana. You can &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dotphoto.com/go.asp?l=sytel&amp;amp;AID=1009419&amp;amp;Pres=Y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;view some photos of this trip&lt;/a&gt;, some are really cool including one with beetles procreating right inside the rose!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jun-July Photo Album</title>
      <link>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/jun-july-2003-photo-album/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2003 05:25:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/jun-july-2003-photo-album/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This quick and small album could be viewed at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dotphoto.com/go.asp?l=sytel&amp;amp;AID=910803&amp;amp;Pres=Y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;dotPhoto&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll post it on my site when I stop being lazzzy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Point State Park</title>
      <link>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/high-point-state-park-nj-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2003 20:51:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/high-point-state-park-nj-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This place is becoming my luxury hike place on lazy drizzly spring days. It&amp;rsquo;s the highest point in state of New Jersey. You can see all neighbouring states Pennsylvania, Connecticut and New York on clear day and you don&amp;rsquo;t even have to hike to get on the top - just take 5 min easy drive and you are there! It has even little beach on the lake. You can view Mohonk, Catskills, Camelback, Pocono&amp;rsquo;s, Bear mountains - all from same place! It&amp;rsquo;s even better on drizzly days because there&amp;rsquo;s no one there and clouds are kissing the land :). Also, by far it&amp;rsquo;s the only perfect sunset view spot I&amp;rsquo;ve found in NJ. To get there, all you have to do is to be on Rt 23N. Just after few miles Rt 23 suddenly becomes all green and gorgeous. The country roads after the town of Franklin are cool enough to get lost for a while. I have a took &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dotphoto.com/go.asp?l=sytel&amp;amp;AID=810813&amp;amp;Pres=Y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;some pics - check it out&lt;/a&gt;! I&amp;rsquo;ll be adding few more soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Of New York</title>
      <link>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/best-of-new-york-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2003 07:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/best-of-new-york-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just keep finding excuses to run away to New York and yet have never ran out of places to go. On the contraray, many have. Here&amp;rsquo;s the coolest link to help you out. These guys have came up with a list of best of everything - from Best Haircut to Best Romantic Hotel. So if you are tired of stumbling on to same old places, here&amp;rsquo;s the gene for you :). &lt;a href=&#34;http://newyork.citysearch.com/best/categories/2002&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://newyork.citysearch.com/best/categories/2002&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Picks: Movies, Concerts And Art</title>
      <link>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/picks-movies-concerts-and-art-mar-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2003 07:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/picks-movies-concerts-and-art-mar-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three movies that you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t miss this season: 1. Chicago - A total classic. Very different. Nice screen play. Cool lightings and photography. These guys got nominated for 13 acadami awards and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t surprised. 2. About Schmidt - A movie that gonna move you. Shatter you. Only for hard core reality fans. 3. The Guru - A cool hilarious flick on an Indina emigrant. Neat. Concerts: 1. Matchbox Twenty is on roll. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.matchboxtwenty.com/tour.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Click here their schedules&lt;/a&gt; for NY/NJ area. 2. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nowrunning.com/eventsFolder/UnityOfLight/ny.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The unity of light&lt;/a&gt; - A concert by my favorite Indian artist A.R. Raheman. This will feature several other BIG artists from Bollywood music scene. Looks very cool to me. Art: The 50th anniversary of the discovery of the double helix is now being celebrated visually, with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2003/03/14/arts/design/14BOXE.html?th&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;six different exhibitions in Manhattan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring The Undergrounds</title>
      <link>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/exploring-the-undergrounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2003 04:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/exploring-the-undergrounds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it&amp;rsquo;s amazing how some of the most beautiful passions are shared by so few. Thanks to a re-routed email that dropped in to my Inbox telling me there was a presentation on &amp;ldquo;All about caves and caving&amp;rdquo; and I got a chance to meet people who are exploring these underground marvels since more then a decade. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty much beginner and just had some idea how these caves would have looked like when I read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0140390839/102-5177515-0440154&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Adventures of Tom Sawyer&lt;/a&gt; a decade ago (and this still remains the best book I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read!) and when I went out on one of the caving trips last summer with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.outdoors.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AMC&lt;/a&gt;. It is simply breathtaking what this planet&amp;rsquo;s underground holds for you with miles and miles long caves nerves system frequently including super huge tall domes formations and sometime hundreds of spiky icy straws, deep pits and even lakes. These caves can be explored almost all year round because temperatures there stays stable between 50-60 F. However it&amp;rsquo;s complete darkness there and you got to have helmet with light and some other essential gear. It&amp;rsquo;s recommended that if you are beginner you go with someone experienced and never go in group of less then four. If you are a good hiker and have some rock climbing experience, it helps but all you really need is a will to crawl, scramble and be there! The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caves.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;National Speleological Society&lt;/a&gt; is your starting point to get in touch with gurus and go out in their group outings across United States and Maxico. If you are in New Jersey, visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nnjg.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Northern New Jersey Grotto&lt;/a&gt; to meet some of the cool experts in this field and start out in their trips designed for beginners!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Around Mumbai</title>
      <link>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/moving-around-mumbai-jan-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2003 06:33:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/moving-around-mumbai-jan-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I never liked the City&amp;rsquo;s new name &amp;ldquo;Mumbai&amp;rdquo; (from old Bombay) but it looks like that&amp;rsquo;s gonna stay. My favorite season to be in the City always had been Monsoon (June - Sep) when it rains a lot. However the weather in December is also pleasant 70s (F) and sky is still clear enough for me to spot some shooting stars. Here I&amp;rsquo;m going to outline few observations as a personal note. If you been to or away from this wonderful, dirty, soulful and one of the greatest cities in the world, here&amp;rsquo;s the treat for you :). The vegetarian and the non-vegetarian sects seem to have risen in equality in their strength and aggressiveness. Vegetarian burgers were already common place but now you can see vegetarian hot dogs on menus! I even saw the ad for vegetarian tooth paste! But on the other hand much of the college going crowed doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel any guilt in eating animals. However, vegetarian burgers are just &amp;ldquo;vada paw&amp;rdquo; with burger&amp;rsquo;s bun. The restaurant staff also informed me that hot dog has same material as burger but with different buns. Looks like the City is reinventing American food just as it did decade ago for Chinese food. Much of the &amp;ldquo;Chinese&amp;rdquo; food available on Bombay&amp;rsquo;s street is something that&amp;rsquo;s most Chinese people are not aware of! Bombay girls, on average, are more free from traditions, modern and sophisticated. However this might be more true for upper middle class and riches. It&amp;rsquo;s not unusual to find girls smoking in college campuses and no one even gives a second look. While I hate smoking, doing it just as free as a man could and without guilt is a good change. In the New Year&amp;rsquo;s party that I been to, the clothing style of the crowd there was undistinguishable from a posh nightclub in US. But then again, that party was sponsored by F TV, a new channel in Bombay on fashion stuff. Now there are many more cable channels available then before. However most western TV channel&amp;rsquo;s have &amp;ldquo;indianized&amp;rdquo; themselves to stay in the fierce competition. The MTV India is far far better in quality and presentation then its native US version. The cable internet is now easily available for nearly same cost as dialup, however numbers of hours are limited and you have to pay hefty sum for a modem. Mobile phones are extremely common place and that looks like a booming business. Most phones use European style SIM cards and have pay-and-go billing. The mobile text messaging (SMS) is very common and can be used across the glob (In US, the text messaging standards are different which makes it neither popular nor globally usable). One of the other visible improvements is the numbers of FM channels that has been mushroomed in the City. I found most of them had real good quality programming. That may not be surprising when you realize that most DJs on these radio stations are young and even possibly still college going crawd instead of government employees. So, you know it&amp;rsquo;s gonna be cool and vibrant stuff. Radio Mirch is one of the nicer ones. There are many more shopping malls then before but still they are quite small (not even 1/4th) compared to giant ones that you can find everywhere in US and UK. Much of the things sold in these malls are direct imports and targeted for relatively rich mass rather then usual middle class. You can get almost anything that&amp;rsquo;s available in western countries: popular colognes, brand sun glasses, Boss home theater system, DVD + MP3 players, big screen TVs, Play Station 2 and so on. But one of the hard to find thing was Calvin Klein Eternity cologne which I&amp;rsquo;d forgot to pack with my luggage at last minute! These new malls are starting the change in retain business but most purchasing still happens in street-side small retail stores. However apart from more shopping malls, what city needs right now is more high rises. I saw old and small buildings being replaced by bigger and better looking ones (usually referred as &amp;ldquo;towers&amp;rdquo; in the City terminology). However these are usually still limited to 7 floors high. I guess much of the city&amp;rsquo;s problems like slum areas, unhygienic places and unorganized shops would be instantly solved by putting up real sky scrappers (50+ floors giants) everywhere like in New York and thus creating sufficient room to accommodate everyone nicely. Unfortunately lately I&amp;rsquo;d heard that some old residents had filed law suits against new high rises and so government is actively thinking about putting a ban on them. The sky scrapers is the reality that have to be accepted at one point or another. Later is not better. There&amp;rsquo;s no escape. Most people in Bombay feels that the City was improved in last few years by several new flyovers and highways. But it seemed minor changes to me and may even go unnoticed if someone doesn&amp;rsquo;t tell you. Local trains now all have 12 coaches. I felt that the pollution in the City had reached to suffocating level. But you hear and see different things. One information board near Thane station said last measured air quality was rated &amp;ldquo;excellent&amp;rdquo; and that board itself I could see standing in smoke. I was guessing UV radiation would be much higher because of this but no one I knew was wearing sun block lotion. All &amp;ldquo;ricks&amp;rdquo; (3-wheelers) and taxies are now required to run on LPG gas rather then gasoline (&amp;ldquo;patrol&amp;rdquo; in City&amp;rsquo;s terminology rather than &amp;ldquo;gas&amp;rdquo; as in US). The drivers hate this law because of long queues to fill up with LPG gas. However from cost, pollution and maintenance point of view everything is better with LPG. I was wondering why LPG driven vehicles are completely absent from UK or US. Anyways, there&amp;rsquo;s fine of Rs. 200 for not wearing seat belts. Though few people cares and infect, taxies has no seatbelts at all even if you want to wear them! I&amp;rsquo;d later realized taxies even don&amp;rsquo;t have side mirrors!! The &amp;ldquo;usual&amp;rdquo; driving style in Bombay might make you loose couple of heartbeats. If you wish, you can even switch to totally opposite side lane so you can pass vehicle in front of you! No traffic fines. Even if you are on extreme right lane at the traffic light, you can still attempt to make a left turn. It&amp;rsquo;s ok. No one cares about divider lines between lanes. Infect for many, its fun to drive exactly on the center of a divider line! Most two lane roads would be used as 3 or 4 or even 5 lane roads. The only widely accepted &amp;ldquo;traffic law&amp;rdquo; seems to that more massive vehicle has a right of way. That means pedestrians, being the least massive things, has no right of way whatsoever. Peds just have to wait. If they happen to break this rule, you are allowed to honk at them. Honking is not an irritation but a normally accepted way of communicating between drivers (no pun). Even some trucks had signs &amp;ldquo;please honk&amp;rdquo; (to let me know you are behind me)! My friend told me that numbers of vehicles are now doubled in the City. But the surprise for me was that I didn&amp;rsquo;t saw a single car accident in entire period of month - something that I&amp;rsquo;m so used to see on Garden State Parkway in New Jersey once a week. That&amp;rsquo;s probably because of low speed limits of 40 KM/hr or less in the Bombay city. I do like to indulge in the conversation with cab and ricks drivers because they often have honest views and good info to share on lower middle class - though you have to take a risk of looking stupid at times if you haven&amp;rsquo;t been around for a while. Your visit is incomplete anywhere you go if you don&amp;rsquo;t sample local food, music, nightclubs and jokes. As far as food is concerned, Bombay is a heaven. I had hard time keeping off myself within limits. The sophisticated restaurants with cool innovative menus and interior decoration have mushroomed everywhere you would care. However, real food in Bombay is the street food. You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t miss that because I haven&amp;rsquo;t found the taste equals even in acclaimed authentic restaurants outside India. The best street food heaven would certainly be the Chaupaty. However, it&amp;rsquo;s advisable that you don&amp;rsquo;t try everything in a single day (like me) because it might easily cause bad stomach problems or even typhoid. You do need some confidence and strong built-in anti-bacterial protection. However bonus is that while eating that stuff you can see a perfect sunset in the ocean, something that&amp;rsquo;s not usual on the East coast in US. Other places to see sunsets in Bombay are Band Stand in Bandra, Marin drive, Jogger&amp;rsquo;s Park and Worli sea face. All of these are cool places to walk around when it&amp;rsquo;s not crowdy. With perfect temperatures of 70s, mild winds coming over your face and beautiful sunset in front of your eyes nothing gets better. The notable one is the Jogger&amp;rsquo;s Park, a clean well maintained sea side place where I saw the last and probably the most beautiful sunset of the year. There was a funny sign in there &amp;ldquo;No Mis-behaving&amp;rdquo;! One of the City&amp;rsquo;s other places to have fun is Waterpark which is a heaven because of hot temperatures all year. This waterpark has put forward a claim for world&amp;rsquo;s biggest water coaster. Also one of the other visible changes in the City is so many brand new coffee houses. The one chain Italian coffee shop called Baristas is all over the City and they happens to have 10x better coffee then Starbucks and 100x better then Dunkin Doughnuts. Yeah, definitely. One of the changes that has struck me the most, painfully, is much more sharper division between lower and upper middle classes. It seems that the former&amp;rsquo;s family income has remained virtually unchanged over the last five years while the average prices of all none-essential goods seems to have been almost doubled. But it&amp;rsquo;s still amazing that most people seemed quite satisfied with their way of living. They didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to miss buying a portable CD player and or going out for playing 10-pin bawling. They think they have fun, they satiesfy their needs and they are rising. I think what constitutes this City is its people then it&amp;rsquo;s geography. Even under rising financial pressures, crushing work hours and increasing inflation, people are still good at heart as they ever have been. You can meet complete strangers, get along with them and have fun without caring each other&amp;rsquo;s last names or financial backgrounds. Only problem is that you might have to tell them that you gonna go away soon. Its might be as well less painful just to disappear&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outdoor Clubs On East Coast</title>
      <link>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/outdoor-clubs-on-east-coast-2002/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2002 20:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/outdoor-clubs-on-east-coast-2002/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are single or have hard time to make you friends get of bed to climb some mountains or paddle some rivers - well, here&amp;rsquo;s something that might interest you. I&amp;rsquo;ve found few huge and really cool organizations that engage themselves in doing some interesting adventure outings in groups. The biggest and the best of these is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sierraclub.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sierra Club&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s purpose of existence is nature conservancy and awareness. Every week they have multiple outings - hikes, kayaks, group dinners, meetings and even outdoor movie shows! The places I&amp;rsquo;d visited with some of the hike leaders this summer were mind blowing, kind of secret gems&amp;hellip; They also have special singles outings which I guess is better place to find that special someone then anywhere else because people who you meet in these clubs are the ones who you can identify with yourself, the spirit of adventure and sense of exploration. The Sierra club is non-profit, has chapter in almost every state in US (I usually go out with NY and NJ chapters) and they excert high influence on US nature policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another huge organization is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.outdoors.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AMC or Appalachian Mountain Club&lt;/a&gt;. They stand out by the diversity and huge quantity of outings they offer - including everything from hiking, sailing, kayaking, tour of Brooklyn bridge, night time Central Park, ice caves, all summer softball at Central Park, camping at their own facilities, windjammer cruises, tree identification walks, a day at Coney Island and so on. In spite of these, I like them less compared to Sierra due to couple of reasons. They don&amp;rsquo;t publish their schedules fully on web and force you to get their printed book. That tiny book takes time to arrive and can easily get misplaced. Many of the hike leaders doesn&amp;rsquo;t have or disclose their email addresses and at many instances, you will find it hard to contact them by any means even if they disclose anything at all. While most the people you will meet are very respectable and pleasant in person, the Sierra&amp;rsquo;s flavor of openness and friendly feel is not as strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last organization on the list is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adk.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ADK or Adirondack Mountain Club&lt;/a&gt;. Actually this is the first one I came to know about before any other. While it&amp;rsquo;s small and locally focused on NY/North NJ, I believe it&amp;rsquo;s the most intimate and friendliest club around. But the coolest things they do which sets them apart from everybody else is their international and national adventure travel. The list includes week-long outings like staying with real Inuit people at Greenland in the way they live, hikes at Swiss Alps, England Coast-to-Coast, trekking with donkeys in France, Grand Canyon backpacking, Alaska rafting and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A last point: I&amp;rsquo;ve often observed that that age proportion at many of these vibrant exciting clubs is not well balanced: numbers of young people (in 20s) is strikingly and surprisingly less. I guess it&amp;rsquo;s responsibility of people like us to spread the word and keep these clubs and spirit alive in the coming time. So get out of the bed and go somewhere!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autumn Fall Foliage Long Drives 2002</title>
      <link>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/autumn-fall-foliage-long-drives-2002/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2002 00:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shitalshah.github.io/p/autumn-fall-foliage-long-drives-2002/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve some more time and it&amp;rsquo;s my first day doing blogs so I&amp;rsquo;ll put down few more tid bits&amp;hellip; This one is about fall foliage travelling I did this year. Last year I went out to 3 day trip to New Hampshire and drove through much of the state. This year I decided to went down North-east Pennsylvania. The driving route at Bucktail State Park was listed as &amp;lsquo;one of the most beautiful spot to be&amp;rsquo; in foliage by Yahoo Travel newsletter. There is some 75 miles of Route 120 which passes through scenic mountainous areas and small towns. So I rented Mustang convertible and started the trip on 20th Oct. Passing through Rough 80 west from NJ to PA was absolutely stunning. Unfortunately you can&amp;rsquo;t stop on highway to take photographs and there are not many view points on Rt 80. So just look around and drive slow. While entering on Rt 120 at Lock Haven, PA I realized the peak was already passed and there was around 40% or less leafs on trees. A big sigh! But this was anyway as predicted in Foliage report at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.FallInPA.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FallInPA.com&lt;/a&gt;. But whatever was left was still absolutely gorgeous. You can tell how beautiful the peak must have been looked like. So after passing Ronovo I decided to drive down south were peak was still expected. I took Rt 144 and I glad I did. This some 70 miles long road was continuously covered with fall colors, passing through deep forest, valleys in curvy snaky ups and down fashion. What a treat! Next year I&amp;rsquo;ll be back here with proper timing :-). Anyway this was not my first trip and not the last also for this year. The first trip I did was to Windham, NY at Catskills. It was annual ADK (www.adk.org) fall weekend with lots of hikes in around the area. I did the 3 summit hike at Thomas Kole (6 mil) and one another 4 miles hike next day. Fall colors were just starting to appear. You can look at photographs on my web site &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ShitalShah.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.ShitalShah.com&lt;/a&gt; or their real host at www.dotphoto.com (the name of the album is First Of Autumn). The next fall color trip WILL be at NYC this weekend at Central Park. I&amp;rsquo;m missing Autumn at NYC since last two years and it&amp;rsquo;s hardly 40 mins away from my home! Sure NYC is jungle of building but Central Park is just a magical place. I saw some Central Park foliage shots in movie Autumn in New York (it appears just when movie starts, good because you don&amp;rsquo;t need to see rest of the crap). This weekend I guess is peak weekend in Central Park.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
