<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Opinions | Shital Shah</title>
    <link>http://shital.com/categories/opinions/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://shital.com/categories/opinions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Opinions</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>(C) Shital Shah. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2009 00:19:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://shital.com/img/shitalshah.jepg</url>
      <title>Opinions</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/categories/opinions/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intel Xeon – the worse branding ever?</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/intel-xeon-the-worse-branding-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2009 00:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/intel-xeon-the-worse-branding-ever/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is really frustrating if you didn’t knew. Intel likes to call many of their processors for “business class” systems “Xeon”. When they say Xeon it can mean anything from those dinosaurs based on Pentium II and the latest and greatest ones based on on Core i7. So when you see a system built with Xeon processor you really need to look up its exact subtle number and carefully study its specs to figure out what it really is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, &lt;a href=&#34;http://ark.intel.com/Compare.aspx?ids=39718,37147,&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Xeon W3520 is same as latest Core i7-920&lt;/a&gt;, including the price. The only difference between two is Xeon supports ECC memory. So what’s the point in branding this processor as Xeon instead of Core 2 i7?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, new Intel Core i7 series is definitely a winner and finally makes 2 year old Intel Core 2 series actually obsolete. This processor can execute 8 threads simultaneously and supports 3 channels for DDR3 access tripling the RAM bandwidth! Best of all, it costs more or less same as older Core 2 processors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oil Prices - Summary of 4 hours of news bits in past month</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/oil-prices-summary-of-4-hours-of-news-bits-in-past-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2008 11:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/oil-prices-summary-of-4-hours-of-news-bits-in-past-month/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I did not knew oil prices had crossed $4 mark and got a huge surprise to see that last Thursday. I don&amp;rsquo;t watch news generally because much of it is irrelevant but after we have set up PC to our TV it&amp;rsquo;s much easier to see exactly what matters. So I was just watching series of MSNBC videos going all the way up to May on oil prices going up, people leaving their RVs behind, people trying to sell out their SUVs, GM planning to dump Hummer, people choosing to do home barbeque instead of traveling for memorial day&amp;hellip; There is a new term called Staycation for people staying home for vacation (we heard another term &amp;ldquo;Junctober&amp;rdquo; to refer to colder windier October like weather in June at our visit to Vason island)! a big dose for me of all of that. However the most worrisome part was airlines cutting down 25% of the seats and tickets sky rocketing 2X to 4X. So I looked up SEA to SLC and fortunately Utah ticket is only gone up by $75 ($225 to $295). Yes, big increase but its not like $600 - yet. It would be painful to think of Utah drifting away from the reach. On the other note, gas prices in Europe and elsewhere is about $8 so it&amp;rsquo;s not very unrealistic that US prices will match up to that in not very long term. However all indications are that if oil prices goes above $5 there will be a crash in economy because lot of businesses are currently trying to swallow this increase in one way or another and with continuous rise all of them will finally dump it on customers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kiwi Berries</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/kiwi-berries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2008 06:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/kiwi-berries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh&amp;hellip; these Kiwi Berries from Te Puke, NZ&amp;hellip; some of the best fruits in the world!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2008/04/img_kiwiberry-packaging.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2008/04/img_kiwiberry-packaging.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img_kiwiberry-packaging&#34; width=&#34;374&#34; height=&#34;236&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-763&#34; srcset=&#34;http://shitalshah.com/ShitalShahWP/wp-content/uploads/2008/04/img_kiwiberry-packaging.jpg 374w, http://shitalshah.com/ShitalShahWP/wp-content/uploads/2008/04/img_kiwiberry-packaging-300x189.jpg 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 374px) 100vw, 374px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why BN.com Has To Suck?</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/why-bn-com-has-to-suck/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2005 15:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/why-bn-com-has-to-suck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written quite some code whose sole users are probably just few dozen people. Even than I&amp;rsquo;d went to extra-ordinary lengths to make sure that code was having highest number of features and ease of use than anything else that existed and was comparable. There are lots of businesses everywhere ranging from car rental companies to book stores who have, unlike me, thousands and thousands of users every single day, staff of hundreds and millions to dollars spend. To add all the cool features in their services that would delight their users every now and than, it would take probably cost a sub-percent of their revenues. Why it doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen? Why it is so hard for Barnes and Nobel to create a website that can proudly stand besides Amazon in slickness, modern looks and innovation? Cost is certainly not the factor. What is it? Why certain part of eco-sphere is doomed to be second class regardless of available resources to them?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things Behind The eBay Deal</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/things-behind-the-ebay-deal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2005 20:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/things-behind-the-ebay-deal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have read more braindead deal than Skype for $2.1 billion. Obviously Skype isn&amp;rsquo;t worth that much (so far it has got investments of under $21M). One could have built much more feature rich, customized software for 1000 times less money than that. What about future? Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t Skype have revenues of zillion dollars in 2010? No, it won&amp;rsquo;t. Biggies like Microsoft and Yahoo are already coming up with similar software with far deeper reach than Skype could ever imagine to have. Plus cable companies are throwing away entire need for computer and microphones and have very soon plans to dial from regular phone and route it through Internet. So why executives at eBay would decide to through away half of their cash in deal that needs everyone to take microscope to find what&amp;rsquo;s so good about it? There are many deals like that have happened in past where people just can&amp;rsquo;t find justification and had just has to go with the aura of the buyer. My guess is that big heads in eBay is going to get, somehow someway, huge cuts in this deal. The thing is that when company has $4B floating in their bank account, its not easy for executives to get it simply transfered in their bank accounts. So you go out, cut the deal to buy $2000 car for $200,000, have seller spend $188,000 on things you liked but which you couldn&amp;rsquo;t have directly spent by yourself. And meanwhile, cross your fingers to have journalists think you are a smart guy and have them keep discussing that there must be something super cool in that car that a visionary like you can see but dumbass journalists like us can&amp;rsquo;t. I meant those journalists which your PR department haven&amp;rsquo;t bought out, yet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Business Experiment</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/the-business-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2005 03:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/the-business-experiment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thebusinessexperiment.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Business Experiment&lt;/a&gt; got initially got me intrigued but then I realized why it would bring only an average results. This experiment basically wants to try running a startup by votes from the people. The idea is to harness &amp;ldquo;wisdom of the crowds&amp;rdquo;. I think, the smartness factor would be averaged out in this system instead of &amp;ldquo;more than sum of its parts&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s blind one-shot voting after all; not a structured logical argument going in the crowed which could otherwise have made difference. Other way to look at it is that such business is already in existence which is virtually run by voting and belief system of crowd: government! It may be fairly robust and may be sufficiently stable over centuries of existence but its the most inefficient business that we know of.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applications And Platforms, An Another Face Of Internet And Why I Hate Groove</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/applications-and-platforms-an-another-face-of-internet-and-why-i-hate-groove/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2005 02:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/applications-and-platforms-an-another-face-of-internet-and-why-i-hate-groove/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.Groove.net&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Groove&lt;/a&gt; is perhaps one of the finest example of technology in recent times which has tons of potential and no vision. If you ask Groove what their product is, they will probably reply with something like this: &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em&gt;program&lt;/em&gt; that allows people to work together on files, projects, meetings and so on.&amp;ldquo;. And that underlines their severe lack of vision and plain immaturity which otherwise could have changed the face of the Internet. What it could have been is this: A &lt;em&gt;platform&lt;/em&gt; that allows developers to build applications that could work online or offline with automatic real-time database and file replication. There is a huge difference between creating an &lt;em&gt;application&lt;/em&gt; and a &lt;em&gt;platform&lt;/em&gt;. To put it in perspective, imagine Microsoft developers betting most of their time and energy to create vast variety of end user applications and paying little or no attention in producing well documented APIs, solid development tools and nurturing, supporting and enticing developer community to enable &lt;em&gt;them&lt;/em&gt; to create applications. Would Microsoft have gone that way it would have become another Apple. And computers would still be privately manufactured expensive white boxes fancied by richies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why I like FireFox so much? If I was using it out of the box and without downloading any extensions, I would have dumped it in trash can right away. Without extentions support, it&amp;rsquo;s not that powerful and cool out of the box as those guys would have like you to believe. But enter the hundreds of cool extensions made by &lt;em&gt;other people&lt;/em&gt;, and FireFox is suddenly the most appealing and powerful browser to me. FireFox extension API has essentially became a platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to create a fast spreading powerful software, the bottom line is simple: Through people the plateform and thou shalt built apps upon it. Invest more in platform, not applications. Groove hasn&amp;rsquo;t learned this lesson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, they are learning. They have VS.Net integration with GTK now, managed wrappers for lot of things, Developer Tools division, more then zero documentation and (are you ready?) even a book! But when you look at all these, you immediately realize that this effort to make Groove as a platform is more like an afterthought, a low priority, a low budget corporate &amp;ldquo;hobby&amp;rdquo; project and definitely an unfocused one. Before GTK came out some hardcore people were still trying to figure out how to use capabilities of Groove even if they had to use JavaScript APIs without documentation! And lot of them even then built cool apps. Imagine what if a real developer friendly platform was available wide open? How many applications would be built upon it? How many people would have downloaded Groove just to use those apps?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So exactly how does Groove fails to deliver to developers? To start with, they are extremely reluctant to change, re-designing, re-factoring, modernizing and rewriting their aged stuff. Their original core engine C++ code and API design is beyond the edge of being outdated and that&amp;rsquo;s an understatement to fully describe the troubles with it. Groove APIs are exposed through COM and has a massive surface area combined with no documentation for much of the part. It&amp;rsquo;s bloated, broken and even not fully implemented in many cases. In latest version 3.0 they have changed their UI makeup (and file share performance) but they are still dragging along ancient under the hood code. Compare that to Microsoft rewriting and renewing their massive operating systems every 5 years or so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current development aids for Groove aren&amp;rsquo;t just enough. Even if you are using VS.Net integration, lots of things needed for real world apps would require you to modify proprietary files in obscure places under the direction of support people. To publish a Groove tool there is &lt;a href=&#34;%20http://www.ischool.washington.edu/groove/solutions/groove_tool_publication.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20+ step procedure&lt;/a&gt;with warnings signs: don&amp;rsquo;t screw up here. For anything more then &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; app, you would have no choice but to sign up with Groove as their partner and hire their super expensive consulting and support services (which on many instances just comes back with replies &amp;ldquo;we never thought you might want to do that with Groove. Sorry, that&amp;rsquo;s not possible.&amp;rdquo;). Groove doesn&amp;rsquo;t realise that the worst way to make money for them would be by squeezing the developer and proding them away for ever. And I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about launching rockets with Groove, but things as trivial as programmatically hiding left pan is simply not possible. And yes, they have the largest surface area API I&amp;rsquo;ve seen anywhere, including Windows. They haven&amp;rsquo;t reused almost anything: everything from files, data, installation - you name it - they have their own proprietary APIs that you need to learn from the scratch (I&amp;rsquo;d spent tons of time and energy to have them support standard ADO.Net instead of their properitory data API and we used it in our project but unfortunetely they have pulled it out from Groove 3.0). I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say those guys at Groove are uncompetitive (I&amp;rsquo;d been to their office for couple of days worth of meetings and those guys were smart and cool), it&amp;rsquo;s just bloated outdated design that they have to live with and work with. What a waste of an outstanding concept&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is lot more to it. Groove isn&amp;rsquo;t good and inviting to developers. Besides terrible &amp;ldquo;partner only access&amp;rdquo; schemes, you will also get recommendations to use their expensive personal training classes (I&amp;rsquo;d been to the one which was a week long). Can you imagine if FireFox didn&amp;rsquo;t fully document their APIs and asked you to sign up for their really expensive training if you&amp;rsquo;d wanted to make extentions for their browser? On most instances you would also end up hiring their &amp;ldquo;per hour&amp;rdquo; support and consulting staff to actually solve your problems that comes dozen a dime in real-world Groove development. I think several companies like IBM, Apple and Oracle workes just in this way and Microsoft is the only one to actually get developers on their side, give them nice tools and make things easily and freely accessible to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several bad unrealistic decisions made during Groove&amp;rsquo;s inceptions are still stuck with it even after almost a decade. For instance, Groove&amp;rsquo;s replicated store is maintained in the encrypted XML files rather then real relational database powerhouse. Those designers wanted plateform independence and they screwed up (such types of failures are becoming so common they deserve a name: &amp;ldquo;Cross-Plateform Wanna Be Failure Pattern&amp;rdquo;). Results? Groove sucks at scalability. In my experience, put more then 15 people in a space or more then 10,000 rows in &amp;ldquo;database&amp;rdquo; and you will be soon thinking about uninstalling Groove. Yet another example of carrying over ancient design misshapes is that the entire Groove engine works only from inside their proprietary &amp;ldquo;Transreceiver&amp;rdquo;. You can&amp;rsquo;t build your own EXE and consume those API from outside (actually you can at very limited extent but it&amp;rsquo;s so ugly even some internal gurus don&amp;rsquo;t want you to try that).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what Groove could have been if they weren&amp;rsquo;t what they have become? Well, they could have given a birth to thousands of applications that could work either online and offline and anywhere. These vast variety of apps would have almost magical capability to synchronize their data with other people and computers. If you look beyond, it&amp;rsquo;s a whole new form of Internet and here is a highlight of what I mean: You won&amp;rsquo;t need a webserver to host your website. You could have just created a &amp;ldquo;space&amp;rdquo;, listed it somewhere and allowed open anonymous invitations to let anybody find it and browse it. So Internet would mostly become the collection of spaces hosted on individual computers instead of collection of web servers. It&amp;rsquo;s far more advanced then client-server model of current Internet and far beyond then traditional file-sharing P2P apps. In that form of Internet, there truely can not be any censorship. You can have your private television station and serve your content to millions of users through distributed P2P network without a need for expensive webservers and requiring huge bandwidth. Same would happen to audio communication that is currently being done by Skype: you get standard P2P plateform to build VoIP and PodCast servers. Traditional websites would have major facelift: HTML would have been replaced by interactive GUI tools that runs in space running under a secured account. Webistes are no more just HTTPs but are fully functional interactive GUI applications. So you see, lots of software you see around - everything from Kazaa to SETI distributed computing screensavers to &lt;a href=&#34;%20http://freenet.sourceforge.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Freenet&lt;/a&gt; to BitTorrent to Skype - are just specific instances of this technology. All of these applications are screaming for common P2P plateform and because there is none, each have their own quick and dirty homegrown one. If Groove concept was done right, it could have been this universal peer-to-peer computing plateform to do all of these in clear homogeneous way and there would have been an avalanche of next generation P2P applications. And that&amp;rsquo;s why I hate Groove for making it not happen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev OS Choice: Windows 2003 Server Or XP</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/dev-os-choice-windows-2003-server-or-xp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2004 00:25:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/dev-os-choice-windows-2003-server-or-xp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.peterprovost.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Peter Provost&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.peterprovost.org/archive/2004/11/04/2067.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;switching to Server 2003&lt;/a&gt;. I want to say: don&amp;rsquo;t do it! I&amp;rsquo;d been using server version of operating system on my dev machines, even on laptops, since I can remember. But now I&amp;rsquo;m about to change my mind for the first time. Windows Server 2003 is not a cutting edge OS any longer. Infect it sucks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You really have to spend lot of time to set it up right to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.msfn.org/win2k3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;reclaim memory and performance&lt;/a&gt;. For example, disabling several services, disabling option for higher performance for services, enabling DirectX manually and so on - it&amp;rsquo;s always been on going job. Even than, I still find my dev box spinning way too much disk then equivalent XP box.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even both OS shares lot many drivers, its sometime amazingly difficult to install some devices for Sever 2003. Infect just couple of years old hardware from Creative and ATI, the XP version of drivers just won&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many new software from Microsoft itself just don&amp;rsquo;t work on 2003. For example, Windows Media Player 10, Microsoft TimeZone etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enhancements from XP SP2 like IE security and Wireless config etc aren&amp;rsquo;t still available for 2003. It looks like users of 2003 are always one step behind in the line to get the new beef and its taking just too long.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Windows Peer-To-Peer SDK and Advanced Networking Pack does not work on 2003.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;DVD playback and built-in CD burning is hard to get working (requires registry tricks and more).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.msfn.org/win2k3/sysrestore.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;no System Restore&lt;/a&gt;!! It might surprise you, but this is true. For this is so-called solid server OS, if file system corrupts, you lost the whole thing. This actually happened with my laptop which I just switched off while hard drives were still spinning and on next boot I was greeted with blue screen with a message that registry was corrupted. This could have been a legitimate power loss also. It was after-midnight and I really needed few things to get done. After an hour of reading docs all around Internet truth revealed: there was no way to bring 2003 back to life because there is no System Restore feature in this OS!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it just appears that Microsoft simply doesn&amp;rsquo;t care if the new software/drivers they released on XP doesn&amp;rsquo;t work on 2003. They just don&amp;rsquo;t care. I really hate this line between server and home OS versions. Everybody knows that this lines have been drawn just to milk more money from fat corporates for so-called server versions. Few might know, XP and 2003 shares almost identical kernels (even OS version numbers are 5.01 and 5.02 respectively). Right now, you choose any flavor of OS, you not gonna get satisfied because something is missing. Its not because of technicality but pure politics of pricing. And thats a shame to Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Would You Like Some Monopoly With That?</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/would-you-like-some-monopoly-with-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2004 23:09:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/would-you-like-some-monopoly-with-that/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some people had really rejoiced when &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.usdoj.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DOJ&lt;/a&gt; started the antitrust lawsuit on Microsoft. I thought it was lame - for people who can&amp;rsquo;t beat Microsoft in any other way. To me it was like suing Mc Donald’s because they are selling their burgers with their own buns instead of giving their customers an option to choose buns from different vendors. Monopolies are the inevitable children of capitalism but they have been declared illegal. In non-software world, people are less sensitive to this legality issues however. Take this: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.enjoytheshow.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Loews theaters&lt;/a&gt; have put a new rule: If customers wants to see movies in their cinema halls, they must throw away the water bottles they are bringing and buy exactly the same bottle from their own stores inside. The employees are specifically instructed to keep an eye to observe this rule and literally force them to throw it away. As you might have guessed, the bottles available at their store are twice in price as everything else they sell. And as you might also know, entire movie theater business works on monopolies, i.e., if Loews is showing some movie, any other theater in the same region cannot show the same movie. None has yet cared about giving customers a choice for cinema halls. I saw people in line wanting to see movie willingly threw away their bottles without giving a thought. This is not the only example. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.consumersunion.org/telecom/cable103.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cable companies work the same way&lt;/a&gt; and so many others. I still think this a natural evoluation of free markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: Want DOJ and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbb.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;BBB&lt;/a&gt; to go after Loews? &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:AskDOJ@usdoj.gov&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Do it here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://complaints.bbb.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Difference Between Local Trains And Express Trains</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/difference-between-local-trains-and-express-trains/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2004 19:49:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/difference-between-local-trains-and-express-trains/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Local trains stops at every station, express train stops between the two.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will AIers Ever Stop Being Dumb?</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/will-aiers-ever-stop-being-dumb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2003 20:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/will-aiers-ever-stop-being-dumb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every time I read and hear something in AI research, it freaks me out. These &amp;ldquo;research&amp;rdquo; people just keeps formulating laws out of thin air without having any strong logical grounds. Every researcher seems to have their own minuscule world of hard and fast rules that they think is capable to explain everything. What&amp;rsquo;s even worse is that they keep day dreaming that if they keep going like this they are not too far from the finally glory. These people have essentially transformed the &amp;ldquo;science&amp;rdquo; of Artificial Intelligence in to a never ending empirical guess game. And this disease is spreading fast everywhere. Now most research studies simply means collecting data, do some statistics and throw some sketchy laws with lots of &amp;ldquo;might be&amp;rdquo; to hungry scientific generals. All you need is some post at Stanford or MIT and you can at least expect that your garbage will occupy shelves of library all over the world. A good example is &lt;a href=&#34;http://murl.microsoft.com/LectureDetails.asp?1032&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this lecture by Doug Lenat of Stanford&lt;/a&gt;. You will see how lots of &amp;ldquo;principles&amp;rdquo; are drawn right away out of the thin air without any justification for their validity and completeness. I think these guys should step back for a while and read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/1888009004&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Newton&amp;rsquo;s Principia&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://aleph0.clarku.edu/~djoyce/java/elements/elements.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Euclid&amp;rsquo;s Elements&lt;/a&gt; just to get feeling of how important it is to approach problem with strong logical grounds rather then &amp;ldquo;just thoughts out of my mind&amp;rdquo;. We don&amp;rsquo;t have &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0262692112/102-3263321-6040950&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;HAL&lt;/a&gt;. But seeing current state of AI, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t surprises me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should Virus Creators Be Punished?</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/192/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2003 02:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/192/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I and Don Rittenburg of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.groove.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Groove Networks&lt;/a&gt; went in to intense arguments over lunch whether person who creates viruses be punished. I took the side that they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be. My point of view was that cyberspace isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly the real world. It&amp;rsquo;s man-made, designed to be anonymous and most importantly by it&amp;rsquo;s inherent nature it&amp;rsquo;s not supposed to be limited by laws. It gives you immense freedom and if you can be stopped by creating bunch of laws by old fat ignorant politicians then it isn&amp;rsquo;t the same. Of course, freedom isn&amp;rsquo;t a free lunch and you have to accept the associated risk and responsibility. I put the virus creation activities as the inherent part of cyber culture and implicit right of cyber-citizens just like free-speech. Don happens to be really good logician and put some really good arguments. His central idea was that just because it&amp;rsquo;s possible, it can&amp;rsquo;t be just allowed. If your car tires are not secured by lock and key, would you let a person to blow air out of them just to demonstrate that it is not secured or just for fun? Is it worth to live under constant fear that your stuff is not really secured and someone somewhere is gonna come and get you and may destroy your life time of work and get away with it without getting punished or even detected? And multiply the hassle by millions who gets affected, loss of hours, possibly life or career threatening consequences to many and lots of not-so-geeky people who just won&amp;rsquo;t be able to get their computers back to normal. Would that be acceptable? From Don&amp;rsquo;s argument, I think I see the aftermath that typical virus author would fail to see or doesn&amp;rsquo;t won&amp;rsquo;t to. I realized that cyberworld isn&amp;rsquo;t just the world of universities and nerds any more but is now married to the real world and is inseparable part of it. And that marriage would mean loss of inherent freedom and bring the laws in. I&amp;rsquo;m now in agreement that they might be allowed to be punished but still believe that punishment shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be stiff: just few months of community services would suffice. That did settle our 40 mins long logical wrestling (or I lost, to put it correctly). My apologies to cyber-citizens for my failure to defend this supposed-to-be law free culture, however :(.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anders Hejlsberg</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/anders-hejlsberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2003 06:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/anders-hejlsberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just watched &lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/theshow/Episode035/default.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MSDN TV&amp;rsquo;s new episode on Managed Code&lt;/a&gt;. The topic is pretty trivial for me but what&amp;rsquo;s exciting is to see one person talking and seating there. I remember my years as a rebellious programmer when followers were few and swimming opposite the popular currents wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy. In all-Unix all-C++ organization I&amp;rsquo;d heavily pushed for tools and style I believed in - even if it meant taking over entire responsibility and work load on me. All those tools that I chose, used and appreciated for the vision it embedded, looked separate pieces of great ideas which just seem to happen to came on my way&amp;hellip; until there was one day when I read a magazine article and came to know there was really only one person behind all of those and all these years: Anders Hejlsberg. Those separate pieces of vision now seems to make a complete picture and so you can imagine how I would have stand in awe of him. As far as world of programming is concerned, Anders is my hero.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Marriage Conjecture</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/a-marriage-conjecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2003 21:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/a-marriage-conjecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I and Sundar usually get in to blazingly fast high information density conversations. The recent one which lasted for 15 min spanned through topics such as best porn available on Net, XSL, marriages, divorce laws in Texas, blogging and ants. I just happened to make a statement with him which I thought worth blogging. So here&amp;rsquo;s what I call &amp;ldquo;The Marriage Conjecture&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;I was thinking marriage is a big thing. You need to have 100% confidence. Your match should be made in heaven. Both of you should love each other deeply. ALL of these thoughts are CRAP.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s a conjecture because nothing seems to disprove this but to the deep of my heart I know it can&amp;rsquo;t be true. So just like usual mathematician, I guess there&amp;rsquo;s something missing here. Feel like throwing a comment? Leave them below!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unethics Of Cloning</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/unethics-of-cloning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2003 06:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/unethics-of-cloning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So what&amp;rsquo;s wrong with cloning? Lot of things. To clone a person, from genetic point of view, is to like learning absolutely nothing from your experiences. It&amp;rsquo;s an effective stop to evolution of a living being. But fortunately, the Vatican church and many other religious people don&amp;rsquo;t have to exercise with reasoning. Their objection to cloning and almost everything else could be put in same old one liner: It&amp;rsquo;s unethical. But why cloning scares lots of people? Imagine, what if you and me could be mass-produced like TV sets in your home? What if we are not really more then complex bio-chemical machines made out of organic mater that could be just as easily produced in factory? Will clone&amp;rsquo;s soul too be mass-produced? Could clone be considered as rebirth of some other person 50 years ago? Would s/he have rebirth? And what about his or her sins? And can clone go to heaven or hell? Apparently religions all over the world are going have tough time again to re-align themselves with reality. But what if we, as Bible says the one who would rule over everything that moves on land, water and sky, are not &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; the center of the universe? For fans of historical scientific stories this is nothing new. In 1600s, The Catholic Church had put Galileo[]&lt;a href=&#34;http://es.rice.edu/ES/humsoc/Galileo/Bio/narrative_7.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; in the court for making announcement that the Earth is not really at the center of universe. It was shocking that nothing really revolves around us except poor old moon. Finally Galileo decided to concede rather the church burn him for making entire human race so insignificant. It was funny though when I saw a press release few years back when &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dslnorthwest.net/~danwilcox/galileo.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Vatican publicly apologized to Galileo&lt;/a&gt; for that 300 year old mistake. Apparently Bible was easier to bend then truth. And as far as I can see, time is coming back with more dosage of insignificancy. This century is going to be the century of genetics and artificial intelligence. These are the two fields that&amp;rsquo;s still unexplored and where growth is raging at exponential rates. Both have possibilities to come up with better &amp;ldquo;beings&amp;rdquo; then we are, of course you can&amp;rsquo;t afford to say that publicly. Just like Galileo&amp;rsquo;s announcement, it&amp;rsquo;s socking and &amp;ldquo;unethical&amp;rdquo;. May be that&amp;rsquo;s impossible or may be that&amp;rsquo;s what evolution destined to or may be we would be end up being a father of smarter kids. But this time the things that should move out of the center seems to be us rather then Earth. And I just keep wishing if I could be just as blunt all mighty Q[]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.startrek.com/library/bios.asp?ID=105545&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt; when he tells Pickard, &amp;ldquo;you are not that significant&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surviving The Thanksgivings</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/surviving-the-thanksgivings-2002/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2002 08:29:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/surviving-the-thanksgivings-2002/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For some, thanksgiving is a day when you wake up in the morning, make a list of people and spend rest of the day to hate them for not being with you. We have come up even with a term &amp;ldquo;Hate Giving Day&amp;rdquo;. So everybody you knew runs away to their families, suddenly all shops and restaurants closes their doors, entire country like falls in to a comma and you poor soul have no where to go! Well, title of this blog is misleading: you not gonna survive this, but sure you can try&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s gonna snow: around 6&amp;rdquo; in New York and this city looks gorgeous in snow. Good opportunity to take cool photographs and email to everybody on your &amp;ldquo;hate list&amp;rdquo;. Also this should provide more intensives to get up from the bed and go for Macy&amp;rsquo;s Thanksgiving Parade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch the movie The Grinch (the Jim Carey one). Watch one more time. Watch over again. In fact you might want to buy this DVD rather then renting it so that you can watch it over and over coming Christmas holidays also.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guess what. The cinemas, Boston Market and Malasian restaurants like Penang is not closed on thanksgiving and here&amp;rsquo;s whole new pool of good movies out: 8 Miles, Harry Potter, Santa Clause 2, a Bond movie and some Indian-English flick called Hollywood Bollywood!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also perfectly valid to go totally lazy. The TV people has got some cool flicks including Star Wars, Antitrust, Miracle On 34th, Vertical Limit and such stuff. To allow yourself not to get up from the bed in case of a &amp;ldquo;time window&amp;rdquo; in between stupid TV stuff, keep some thick book handy. And yes, don&amp;rsquo;t forget to watch The Grinch in between. Suggested Listening: My December - Linkin Park&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy ruining your hate giving.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look, What&#39;s Time Has Done</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/look-whats-time-has-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2002 07:05:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/look-whats-time-has-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month there&amp;rsquo;s something strange happening in my inbox. Lots of those emails are marriage invitations and some from the people who I knew as &amp;ldquo;geeks&amp;rdquo;. And then I start remembering those days when we set in college labs until late, many times whole night and most of the time escaping from scheduled lectures. The girlfriends and dating was the least of the priority when there is a whole world with challenges in front of you to explore and win (partially that was also eased by the fact that only few female souls thought it worthy to pursue engineering as a field of study). We were tough, proud and ignorent.Some of us thought they don&amp;rsquo;t want to live beyond 30s because it looked too boring. Most of us unanimously thought getting married, silently settling down and disappear in the mass of other 4 billions would be the worst possible way one can live a life. Today I still see likes of these people around. But for the eyes who knew them, there is a subtle difference. The faces doesn&amp;rsquo;t have loud signs of a rebel - rather it looks more like tired fat exploiters. People expect our curiosity to age with us. You don&amp;rsquo;t see people in their middle 30s and 40s roaming around science museums just by themselves - they are not supposed to be that curious! Aging is an interesting process and there was a debate: Is it imperfection or a necessity? While for most it&amp;rsquo;s depressing to even discuss, the study of aging at cellular and genetic level is a fascinating biological paradox. One of the best work I&amp;rsquo;ve came across is a book called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0195153758/qid=1038379694/sr=1-4/ref=sr_1_4/002-0203858-4756001?v=glance&amp;amp;s=books&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A Means To An End&lt;/a&gt;. While still written for a lay-person, it explores scientific theaories of aging without shying away from the technical language of molecular biology and genetics. However as a human beyond mass of bio-chemicals perhaps more interesting is the experience and emotions attached with aging. When I was cruising through that book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0141000511&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hackers&lt;/a&gt;, one of the things I anxiously wanted to know was what happened to those super hard-core computer geeks of 1960s. Where they are, what they are doing today and most importantly, are they the same? If not, where the compromises have made it&amp;rsquo;s home? Author has put this information in the very last chapter and to read it is like reading the Revelation in the Bible. Watching a movie of a large building being demolished with carefully planned explosives has different sets of emotion. Is it fun? scary? Exciting? Disappointing? This experience is perhaps best written in a tiny book by G. H. Hardy written in 1950s called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0521427061/ref=cm_wl_ovu-pg.1-pos.1/002-0203858-4756001?v=glance&amp;amp;coliid=IR2LUAG3S73Q7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A Mathematician&amp;rsquo;s Apology&lt;/a&gt;. When mathematicians - the people obsessed with reality, people with the eyes of pure logic rather then good or evil - writes about emotions it ought to shine like a dew on the rock. When I read this book couple of years ago I thought I&amp;rsquo;d like to carve it in stones so it&amp;rsquo;s there even if humanity manages to loose it&amp;rsquo;s every printed copy. The book cold heartedly deals with author&amp;rsquo;s diminishing abilities for mathematics with his age and one of the most passionate arguments for doing mathematics. Pretty much every paragraph in this book you can put as a quote on your walls! However it couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been more cold hearted then one of that interesting finale of Star Trek Voyager. Most fiction ends either in good thing or bad thing - but not the most probable reality. An average life of human population, with no magic and no coincidences, usually doesn&amp;rsquo;t interest fiction writers. But that Voyager finale appeared to be little different - for first few minutes i.e. The characters who you came to adore are now shown old, have white hair, have wrinkles, some of them already died, some of them insane and most of them looks helpless. Watching your strong heroes ending up in their aged weak state, their lives passed by without any magic is watching reality working like a knife made out of ice. Not everybody can take it. And so after those few minutes, authors of Voyager finale soon puts in some magic and attempts to sweetens their pill. Funny. And there was this quote somewhere: time is the only critic - everyone else has just opinions and fantasies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
