<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music | Shital Shah</title>
    <link>http://shitalshah.com/categories/music/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://shitalshah.com/categories/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Music</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>(C) Shital Shah. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2005 18:36:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://shitalshah.com/img/shitalshah.jepg</url>
      <title>Music</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/categories/music/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endless Columns</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/endless-columns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2005 18:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/endless-columns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are only few tracks &lt;a href=&#34;http://music.yahoo.com/track/1781258&#34; title=&#34;Blue Man Group - Endless Columns&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;that&lt;/a&gt; can be so immensly philosophical and still be modern and classy. Ofcourse, there are no vocals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pavlov&#39;s Dog</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/pavlovs-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2005 19:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/pavlovs-dog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BNL certainly has some scientific lyrics. The &amp;ldquo;Pavlov&amp;rsquo;s dog&amp;rdquo; mentioned in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lyricsfreak.com/b/barenaked-ladies/13335.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Brian Wilson&lt;/a&gt; is about the classic experiment conducted by Pavlov in 1900s to show that dogs can learn to associate ringing of bell to the arrival of food and keep salivate even if you stop giving food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On another note, &amp;ldquo;Nine-point-eight straight down&amp;rdquo; in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lyricsfreak.com/b/barenaked-ladies/13331.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;When I Fall&lt;/a&gt; is the Earth&amp;rsquo;s gravitational constant &lt;em&gt;g&lt;/em&gt; when an object freely falls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There aren&amp;rsquo;t possibly better ways writing about science experiments in more artistic ways in mainstream songs 😉&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Genres To Explore</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/music-genres-to-explore-nov-2004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 22:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/music-genres-to-explore-nov-2004/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are like me and constantly run out of fresh new music to listen, here&amp;rsquo;s something that might help. The best way to discover new music is to find new/fresh/weird genres. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to put here a list of very interesting select genres that I came across recently. I would highly recommend services like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.listen.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rhapsody&lt;/a&gt; if you want to explore these. What’s more important is the way they provide navigation and ability to discover more. For example, once you find an interesting album, you can immediately click on the music genre that album belongs to and then find out the top chart for that genre and discover even more artists and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here are some cool and weird music genres to explore 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laptronica - This is basically music created by single person entirely by high-end software on his or her laptop. Some of popular laprtronica artists even have their concerts where they just sit on the stage with their laptop and stream out some beats for the audience! Example artist M83.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experimental - This is the awesome genre to explore and can keep you busy for hours. Try Blue Man Group&amp;rsquo;s Audio album or a &lt;a href=&#34;http://launch.yahoo.com/song/default.asp?songID=3363203&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;super-weird track by Tom Waits&lt;/a&gt; and you&amp;rsquo;ll know what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solo Instrumentalist - Example artist Itzhak Perlman.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Age/Solo Instrumental - Example artist David Lanz. These for some &amp;ldquo;non-intruding softer displays of creativity&amp;rdquo; times :).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Age Acoustics - Example artist George Winston. These are for some happy relaxing &amp;ldquo;find your soul&amp;rdquo; times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Space Age Bachelor Pad - Yes, that’s really a name of a music genre! Example artist Pizzicato Five.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cut &amp;amp; Paste - Too abstract to be classed as hip-hop, kind of beat-based experiments. Example artist Cold cut.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Electroclash - Energetic synth, electro-techno-pop-punk hybrid. Example artist Fischerspooner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bleep - Moody robotic sounds, too irregular for the dancefloor yet often too disruptive for passive listening. Pretty cool worktime music. Example artist Autechre.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dream Pop - So how about an album named &amp;ldquo;Transient Random-Noise Bursts With Announcements&amp;rdquo; by Streolab?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from these, there is a lot to explore in Foreign, Comedy and Theater genres too. But that some other time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DVD-Audio Format</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/dvd-audio-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 21:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/dvd-audio-format/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&#34;http://shitalshah.com/p/blue-man-group-and-polyphonic-spree/&#34;&gt;recent quest&lt;/a&gt; to find new music, I bumped in to brand new &lt;a href=&#34;http://searchstorage.techtarget.com/sDefinition/0,,sid5_gci510035,00.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DVD-A format&lt;/a&gt; on which many &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/browse/-/574074/102-8083421-0521740&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;new demanding music albums&lt;/a&gt; are being delivered. It appears that this is definitely the next generation of music quality but there is very little or no information on many of its aspects. Here I&amp;rsquo;ll try to summarize what I found so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This format is capable of delivering very high quality multi-channel surround sound on your home theater system. The DVD-A format is entirely different than usual &lt;a href=&#34;http://home.clear.net.nz/pages/adbarr/page1.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dolby Digital or DTS&lt;/a&gt; which is used for DVD movies. The quality that could be delivered using DVD-A is superior than Dolby Digital or DTS. If you look in to your DVD disk in Windows Explorer, you will find that there are two folders: Audio_TS and Video_TS. So far, only Video_TS folder was used to put all the movie files on DVDs because industry wasn&amp;rsquo;t settled on standards for DVD-A format. Recently standards have been finalized and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/browse/-/574074&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;loads of new music albums&lt;/a&gt; are now being released in this format. They have content inside Audio_TS folder which contains DVD-A audio tracks in files with extension .aob. Because its brand new format, you need &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digitalaudioguide.com/dareview/players.htm#da%20(DVD-Audio)%20Players&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;newer DVD players&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.soundblaster.com/products/Audigy2ZS_platinum_pro/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;sound cards&lt;/a&gt; to play it. However because most people aren&amp;rsquo;t going to upgrade their DVD players soon, these audio DVDs supply same sound tracks in Video_TS folder encoded in usual Dolby Digital or DTS which all players knows how to play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now say you buy an audio album on DVD disc. Obviously you can&amp;rsquo;t play it on car stereo or your portable MP3 players because it’s a DVD disc rather than normal audio CD. Or you might want to take backup of your DVD-A disc as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windows/windowsmedia/domorewith/sursoshowcase.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;WMA Pro&lt;/a&gt; files on your PC whcih allows 7.1 surround sound and playback. So what you do? You need to convert DVD disc in to normal Audio disc or rip tracks to MP3s. Unfortunately this isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. The DVD-A format employs &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.extremetech.com/article2/0,1558,1638228,00.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;higher level of encryption&lt;/a&gt; than usual DVDs. The DVD videos (stored in .vob files) employs copy protection scheme called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.extremetech.com/article2/0,1558,1638226,00.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CSS&lt;/a&gt; which can be broken in to very easily using DeCSS or even more friendly &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dvddecrypter.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DVD Decryptor&lt;/a&gt;. But &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digitalaudioguide.com/faq/dvd-audio/faq_intro.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DVD-A format&lt;/a&gt; which was developed later has learned lesson from this hack and currently there is no known way to decrypt .aob files which contains DVD-A audio tacks. That means you can&amp;rsquo;t rip MP3s out of AOB files. Your only way out is to rip off from slightly lower quality Dolby/DTS formatted tracks. The most reliable and easy to use software to do this is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.castudio.org/dvdaudioextractor/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DVD Audio Extractor&lt;/a&gt;. Fortunately many DVD-A albums also provides &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.videohelp.com/forum/archive/t140530.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LPCM&lt;/a&gt; version of tracks along with AC3 (i.e. Dolby Digital)/DTS format. So to burn normal audio CDs or MP3s you might want to choose LPCM version. If DVD-A disc &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/B000051S65/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain LPCM tracks&lt;/a&gt;, than you are out of luck. The down-mix/demux process employed by most software to convert surround sound from AC3/DTS to plain stereo format doesn&amp;rsquo;t produce same quality as commercially available stereo tracks. Though you can try &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.trevormarshall.com/byte_articles/byte7.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;some equations&lt;/a&gt; to combine 5.1 channels in to stereo using SoftEncode etc and usually DTS works better than AC3.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blue Man Group and Polyphonic Spree</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/blue-man-group-and-polyphonic-spree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 19:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/blue-man-group-and-polyphonic-spree/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[Artists - Album]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://launch.yahoo.com/album/default.asp?albumID=1013377&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Blue Man Group - Audio&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My short review of this album would be &amp;ldquo;Insanely creative&amp;rdquo;. This amazing Niagara of energy is probably very different than anything you have heard so far. Some of the tracks were composed with 15 different instruments including PVC pipes and homebrewed hybrid instruments! If you have seen &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blueman.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;their off-Broadway show&lt;/a&gt;, you will probably appreciate this music even more. This show is definitely one of the most creative, energetic, artistic and amusing I&amp;rsquo;ve ever been too. On other note, they have second album called &lt;a href=&#34;http://launch.yahoo.com/album/default.asp?albumID=1089095&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Complex&lt;/a&gt;. In sharp contrast, this album, apparently containing many vocals, comes nowhere close to their first. This album is available in full-blown multi-track surround DVD-A format however it doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain LPCM stereo tracks, which might force you to by normal CD for MP3 extraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://launch.yahoo.com/album/default.asp?albumID=1090842&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Polyphonic Spree - The Beginning Stages Of Polyphonic Spree&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give you a highlight, &lt;a href=&#34;http://launch.yahoo.com/artist/artistFocus.asp?artistID=1099316&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this group&lt;/a&gt; is composed of 20 members including 9 dedicated just for choir, humming and making noises. They are also the only one I know of using French horn. The combined effect of this huge mix and diverse instruments is just majestic while recording quality of vocal is not as good but you probably won&amp;rsquo;t care for the kind of upbeat energy it pours in. While anyone would agree they sound amazing in live concert than on recorded media, I still believe &lt;a href=&#34;http://launch.yahoo.com/artist/default.asp?artistID=1027398&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Trans-Siberian Orchestra&lt;/a&gt; has still maintained its &amp;ldquo;absolute best&amp;rdquo; position with me as far as large bands are concerned. Unfortunately Beginning Stages isn&amp;rsquo;t available in surround DVD-Audio format. However their second album &lt;a href=&#34;http://launch.yahoo.com/album/default.asp?albumID=1110014&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Together We Are Heavy&lt;/a&gt; is indeed available in incredible crystal clear DVD-A surround format but it is probably half as good :(.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These albums are available on &lt;a href=&#34;http://rhapsody-app.listen.com/rhapsody_tour/page1.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rhapsody&lt;/a&gt;, although not in surround sound.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That Song In American Beauty</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/that-song-in-american-beauty/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2004 23:04:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/that-song-in-american-beauty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay&amp;hellip; found that! That song in the movie &lt;a href=&#34;http://http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0169547/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;American Beauty&lt;/a&gt; with rain falling in one of the last scenes is &lt;a href=&#34;http://launch.yahoo.com/song/default.asp?songID=609626&#34; target=&#34;new&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Let It Bring You Down By Neil Young&lt;/a&gt;. Though &lt;a href=&#34;http://launch.yahoo.com/song/default.asp?songID=716366&#34; target=&#34;new&#34;&gt;one by Annie Lennox&lt;/a&gt; is much better. It was buzzing in my head since quite some time now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Triple Mix</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/windham-hill-sampler-best-of-yanni-maroon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2004 23:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/windham-hill-sampler-best-of-yanni-maroon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought I&amp;rsquo;d nothing new to listen to but then just brewed up this triplet which nicely works out on these winter days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://launch.yahoo.com/album/default.asp?albumID=117257&#34; target=&#34;new&#34;&gt;A Winter&amp;rsquo;s Solstice VI&lt;/a&gt;: A Windham Hill Sampler - A nice classical album. Just by look at the track names like Northern Lights, January Stars, Snow Dance, This Clearness Of Light - you know it&amp;rsquo;s gonna be good :).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://launch.yahoo.com/album/default.asp?albumID=1038875&#34; target=&#34;new&#34;&gt;The Very Best Of Yanni&lt;/a&gt;: Yet another good (if not as great) keyboard fiesta. Nice tracks: Flight Of Fantasy, In The Morning Light, The Mermaid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://launch.yahoo.com/album/default.asp?albumID=1029454&#34; target=&#34;new&#34;&gt;Maroon&lt;/a&gt;: Surprisingly good for those &amp;ldquo;missing&amp;rdquo; times when there is too much to do and absolutely nothing do. This my Barenaked Ladies Firsts which probably one can never get tired of hearing one more time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listen As: Random &lt;a href=&#34;http://rhaplinks.listen.com/rhaplink?playlist=Winter%20Solstice%20and%20Yanni&amp;cobrand=40120&amp;tracks=5889404,5889405,5889406,5889407,5889408,5889409,5889410,5889411,5889412,5889413,5889414,5889415,5889416,5889417,5889418,4547239,4547240,4547241,4547242,4547243,4547244,4547245,4547246,4547247,4547248,4547249,4547250,4547251,4547253,5839283,5839284,5839285,5839286,5839287,5839288,5839289,5839290,5839291,5839292,5839293,5839294&#34; target=&#34;new&#34;&gt;The entire play list&lt;/a&gt; is available on &lt;a href=&#34;http://music.lycos.com/rhapsody/&#34; target=&#34;new&#34;&gt;Rhapsody&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barenaked Ladies Live!</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/barenaked-ladies-live-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2003 04:14:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/barenaked-ladies-live-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bnlmusic.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Barenaked Ladies&lt;/a&gt; will be performing live at New York on 22nd Oct. These guys concerts (there&amp;rsquo;s no female members in the band - for the unawares) are among the most fun live events, so don&amp;rsquo;t delay in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ticketmaster.com/event/00003730D89B9217?brand=&amp;amp;artistid=749433&amp;amp;majorcatid=10001&amp;amp;minorcatid=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;getting tickets&lt;/a&gt;! Even more, these are the few of rare artists who prefer to perform live and then put the song in a album rather then other way around. I didn&amp;rsquo;t thought they would be doing any tours. &lt;a href=&#34;http://launch.yahoo.com/musicvideos/player/default.asp?videoID=173975&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pinch me&lt;/a&gt; if I&amp;rsquo;m still asleep 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evanescence @ Webster Hall, NYC</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/evanescence-webster-hall-nyc-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2003 02:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/evanescence-webster-hall-nyc-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://launch.yahoo.com/artist/default.asp?artistID=1098798&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Evanescence&lt;/a&gt; will be performing live at Webster Hall on 16th Sep in New York City as part of their tour. This is little unusual because even the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webster-hall.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Webster Hall&lt;/a&gt; is kind of the top dance club in the City, I never heard any concerts happening there. But probably thats what makes this cool. Check for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nintendofusiontour.com/tour_dates.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;tickets and other tour locations&lt;/a&gt;. But beaware, tickets are being distributed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ticketmaster.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the worst ticketing site in the world&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MTV VMAs</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/mtv-vmas-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2003 02:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/mtv-vmas-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before I go to bed, few more bits&amp;hellip; This is to announce that this year&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mtv.com/onair/vma/2003/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;VMA&lt;/a&gt; sucked. I used to see this show for it being totally different from other award functions (i.e. freaky, weird, explicit and eye-popping). It seems to be the general opinion that if it hadn&amp;rsquo;t been for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mtv.com/onair/vma/2003/postshow/flipbooks/on_stage/topflip.jhtml?c=3&amp;amp;pf=/onair/vma/2003/postshow/flipbooks/on_stage/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Britney-Madonna&amp;rsquo;s kiss&lt;/a&gt;, this would have been the worse so far.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool Albums Of The Season</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/albums-of-the-season-aug-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2003 19:52:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/albums-of-the-season-aug-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s some from shopping list of past few months:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Artist - Album]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linkin Park - Meteora&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evanescence - Fallen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audioslave - Audioslave&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Macy Gray - On How Life Is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Barenaked Ladies - Rock Spectacle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 Strings - Take me away (into the night)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evanescence&amp;rsquo;s Fallen is probably the best thing came out this year. Audioslave is raw, hard and grungy. How Macy Gray came in to my list? I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;d written bad things about Meteora previously but when you are in real need for extreme screaming, lots of hatred and hard hard hard stuff these guys seems to fit the bill.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yahoo! Launch Getting Better</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/yahoo-launch-getting-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2003 15:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/yahoo-launch-getting-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My favorite online music service Rhapsody is not working for me these days. They &lt;em&gt;removed&lt;/em&gt; entire Linkin Park collection, few albums from Kid Rock and God knows what more. So I&amp;rsquo;m back to my old favorite Yahoo! Launch. They have gotten better with more selection, many more videos and more features. The best thing is, ofcourse, you can tell it what you liked and it will select more your kinda music rather then purely random songs. And it&amp;rsquo;s totally free! You can &lt;a href=&#34;http://launch.yahoo.com/lc/?rt=0&amp;amp;rp1=0&amp;amp;rp2=1214708279&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;listen to my own customized radio station&lt;/a&gt; which I&amp;rsquo;m listening to right now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central Park Summerstage and 311</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/central-park-summerstage-2003-and-311/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2003 20:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/central-park-summerstage-2003-and-311/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Central Park summer stage schedule is out. Mark your dates from their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.summerstage.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;official home page&lt;/a&gt;. On 311, this is a new number you can dial in New York and ask any question or make any complaints - literally! This is due to effort of new mayor Bloomberg to combine several agency to one spot through one number! Want to know how to dispose refrigerator? or complain about that loud car alarm? Dial 311.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jewel Moments</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/jewel-moments-central-park-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2003 15:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/jewel-moments-central-park-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shitalshah.com/images/posts/2003/06/jewel_intution.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://shitalshah.com/images/posts/2003/06/jewel_intution-247x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jewel_intution&#34; width=&#34;247&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; class=&#34;alignleft size-medium wp-image-1111&#34; srcset=&#34;http://shitalshah.com/ShitalShahWP/wp-content/uploads/2003/06/jewel_intution-247x300.jpg 247w, http://shitalshah.com/ShitalShahWP/wp-content/uploads/2003/06/jewel_intution.jpg 413w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 247px) 100vw, 247px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On one fine spring morning, a beautiful lady with the sweetest voice decided to walk in a gorgeous park and sing for whoever cared. It was Saturday morning, one of the least busy time of the week when rest of the world prefers to sleep after long Friday night. It was one of the most invisibly promoted concert - even a professional certified guide at Central Park just 200 feet away from the stage didn&amp;rsquo;t knew about it! But still many of us did knew and hassled through early Saturday morning to be there. There were even fans who literally set up their front line spaces before sun came up. Then there was a &amp;ldquo;Jewel stalker&amp;rdquo; who tried a stunt to reach her with roses. Jewel being inherently very shy and sensitive, you don&amp;rsquo;t expect lots of fun fair on the stage. It goes smoothly with occasional emotional bursts until she feels comfortable with the whole thing. And then she can tell jokes and attempt to be funny. She doesn&amp;rsquo;t try to create exact replica of her album versions, instead almost always she would change tempo, tones and add twists. One often discussed disappointment was new hair style (change from the one with &lt;a href=&#34;http://shitalshah.com/images/posts/2003/06/jewel_intution.jpg&#34;&gt;long beautiful hair&lt;/a&gt;). She is sure my #1 favorite female artists and I been envy of people who heard her live when she still a coffee house singer. Her open air concert in the world&amp;rsquo;s greatest city and gorgeous park on that fine spring morning just looked like falling from the heaven. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dotphoto.com/go.asp?l=sytel&amp;amp;AID=810156&amp;amp;Pres=Y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Catch her few glimpse in my photo albums section&lt;/a&gt;. Her new album &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/B00008OWZE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;0304&lt;/a&gt; is already in the stores and I guess she might have &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jeweljk.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;more upcoming events&lt;/a&gt; in case you are interested.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Albums From My Favorite Artists</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/new-albums-from-my-favorite-artists-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2003 04:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/new-albums-from-my-favorite-artists-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[Many of these albums are also available at &lt;a href=&#34;http://music.lycos.com/rhapsody&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rhapsody&lt;/a&gt;.] Suddenly all of my top 3 favorite artists have relased their new music albums during last few months. Unfortunetely all of these albums sucks. But anyway, because they are my favorite they will get metion here :). First, Matchbox Twenty has came up with new album &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/B00006OFTZ/104-3078521-0712709&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;More Than You Think You Are&lt;/a&gt;. Yes, they continue in tradition of weired names for their albums (oh well&amp;hellip; who can make sense of name Matchbox Twenty itself?). I guess they have grown big in last few years but haven&amp;rsquo;t completely lost their touch. Some tracks are cool. It takes time, experiences, situation to get taste of music from these guys. So far I personally know only one person who likes Matchbox Twenty!! Next, Linkin Park is out with much-awaited &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B00008H2LB/104-3078521-0712709&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meteora&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;d though this will be something new and fresh but it totally smells like leftover of their previous hit &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/B00004Z459/104-3078521-0712709&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hybrid Theory&lt;/a&gt;. These guys have so much energy and imagination I&amp;rsquo;d thought it&amp;rsquo;s not gonna wear them down any sooner. Hopefully they have something cooler in pipeline. Finally, Jewel has got her new single Intuition out. She does hip-hop kind of thing for the first time and pretty much screws it up. She has her new full album &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/B00008OWZE/104-3078521-0712709&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;0304&lt;/a&gt; set to be released on June 3, 2003. Hopefully that isn&amp;rsquo;t all that bad. So if these sucks, what&amp;rsquo;s cool? Listen to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B00006JJ1O/104-3078521-0712709&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;200 Km/H in the Wrong Lane&lt;/a&gt;. If while listening some of the lyrics doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to make sense, just remember that this album is from duo of teenaged Russian lesbians (and yes, they are hot!). Another is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/stores/artist/glance/-/73666/104-3078521-0712709&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Barenaked Ladies&lt;/a&gt;. These canadian guys had most of their releases in last decade, have huge followings and their concerts are considered to be one of the best to go for. Very cool guitar tabs seemlessly going with equally cool vocals and effortlessly flowing lyrics and hummable tunes. If you think they took cheap marketing uproach, wait until you listen to tracks like Pinch me, If I should fall or Light up my room. Yes, there is NO female member in the band, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure you won&amp;rsquo;t care.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Picks: Movies, Concerts And Art</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/picks-movies-concerts-and-art-mar-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2003 07:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/picks-movies-concerts-and-art-mar-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three movies that you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t miss this season: 1. Chicago - A total classic. Very different. Nice screen play. Cool lightings and photography. These guys got nominated for 13 acadami awards and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t surprised. 2. About Schmidt - A movie that gonna move you. Shatter you. Only for hard core reality fans. 3. The Guru - A cool hilarious flick on an Indina emigrant. Neat. Concerts: 1. Matchbox Twenty is on roll. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.matchboxtwenty.com/tour.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Click here their schedules&lt;/a&gt; for NY/NJ area. 2. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nowrunning.com/eventsFolder/UnityOfLight/ny.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The unity of light&lt;/a&gt; - A concert by my favorite Indian artist A.R. Raheman. This will feature several other BIG artists from Bollywood music scene. Looks very cool to me. Art: The 50th anniversary of the discovery of the double helix is now being celebrated visually, with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2003/03/14/arts/design/14BOXE.html?th&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;six different exhibitions in Manhattan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Finds: 7 Ethnic Tracks</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/music-finds-7-ethnic-tracks-jan-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2003 07:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/music-finds-7-ethnic-tracks-jan-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite &amp;ldquo;soul test&amp;rdquo; for a song had been to make someone listen to it who doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand the language and see if they can still figure out the meaning from rhythm and vocal emotions. All of the following tracks are &amp;ldquo;remixed&amp;rdquo; versions of original tracks (if there were any), have sweet vocals and certainly has a different style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[artist - album - song]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deep Forest - Pure Moods - Sweet Lullaby. Probably an African language. My guess for this song was that it&amp;rsquo;s a song for pre-marriage rituals and I was wrong for both guesses. You can find english translation from Internet but give yourself a try!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deep Forest - Boheme - Marta&amp;rsquo;s Song. This one is pretty old (released in 1995). Rest of the album is crap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Karunesh - Global Spirit - Punjab. Probably a version of folk song in an Indian language Punjabi. Extremely popular 2002 hit in India. Karunesh is a German born artist who later came to India after near-fatal motorbike accident which started off his spiritual journey.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Khalid - Khalid - Didi. After you listen to Arabic languages you might wonder, if one can even sing in that. This old global hit might prove you wrong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DJ Aqeel - Ek Haseenna thi - Tu Tu Wahi. One of the Bombay style remix but with very cool vocals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instant Karma - Dance Masti Again - Aaja Piya. Yet another Bollywood remix with cool vocals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bally Sagoo - Best of Bally Sagoo - Gur Nalon Ishq Mitha. The bhangra-style music is well known to make your feet move. And when that gets remixed by Bally Sagoo, it a definite dance hit. Much of the album is also not too crapy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Music Finds</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/new-music-finds-nov-2002/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2002 06:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/new-music-finds-nov-2002/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I missed Central Park visit this Sunday. So now this is happening 3 years in row. Anyway, this blog is about the new cool music artists/albums I found in past few months. It&amp;rsquo;s starts with Linkin Park&amp;rsquo;s Hybrid Theory. To say the least, this is the one we call it &amp;ldquo;a land mark&amp;rdquo;. Very artsy compositions, meaningful smart lyrics and the best part: hybrid of melody and metal. You can&amp;rsquo;t possibly miss this one. I haven&amp;rsquo;t heard so much &amp;ldquo;visual&amp;rdquo; music in such quantity and quality. No, you need not be &amp;ldquo;metal&amp;rdquo; guy to listen to this. However the word of caution: many of the lyrics and song styles in this album can drive you in to frustration, illusionary fears or induce suicidal thoughts. You do need to be strong to listen to this and very strong to enjoy it. Next on the list is Jewel. When I heard her voice for the first time I was almost stunned by the sweetness and soul embedded in her voice. And to this date, I consider her as the best female vocals on the planet. She writes her own songs though many of them I consider sucks (her poetry book is available on Amazon). Few totally outstanding numbers: &amp;ldquo;Absence Of Fear&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Time After Timely&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Break Me&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;My Hands Are Small&amp;rdquo;. The first one, the &amp;ldquo;Absence Of Fear&amp;rdquo;, I consider the best love song ever written and sung. Many compare (and occasionally mistakes) her to Cranberries but I guess the &amp;ldquo;souls&amp;rdquo; these two artists put in their songs have different identities. To hear Jewel is treat to ears and thanks to modern day technology, it&amp;rsquo;s available to entire world! I&amp;rsquo;ll include few of my old finds later but before I log out, here&amp;rsquo;s the very latest: DJ Sammy! I randomly picked up his new CD &amp;ldquo;Heaven&amp;rdquo; in the sale at Wiz hoping to hear some cool trans and I glad I did. This is almost perfect (11 out of 13 tracks are vibrantly cool) and easily the second best techno-trans album after Moby&amp;rsquo;s Play. Tracks are full of life and energy and there&amp;rsquo;s no repetition&amp;hellip; The creativity poured in this album is amazing. Most of the tracks are seamlessly combined with very cool female vocals from Yanou (though she hasn&amp;rsquo;t got much credit on front CD cover) - a voice with unparalleled sweetness, imagination and passion. Another peculiar quality of this album is that as you hear it too much, instead of getting dull, it keeps getting better - it&amp;rsquo;s been kind of longest lived CD in my car&amp;rsquo;s player (i.e. 5 days). You need not be trans-junkie to like this album. It will catch your ears whoever you are. Only thing, being an import CD (euro dance) it costs lot: $18 to $25.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Of Blog - How To Carry 10,000 CDs With You</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/first-of-blog-how-to-carry-10000-cds-with-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2002 23:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/first-of-blog-how-to-carry-10000-cds-with-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first blog&amp;hellip; wonder why didn&amp;rsquo;t started this already! First what&amp;rsquo;s Astrila? I can&amp;rsquo;t tell for sure but it probably means &amp;ldquo;sparkling snow in star light&amp;rdquo; in Eskimo&amp;rsquo;s language. Well some don&amp;rsquo;t agree however. I&amp;rsquo;ve my personal web site at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ShitalShah.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.ShitalShah.com&lt;/a&gt; - that&amp;rsquo;s my name Shital Shah. This blog I&amp;rsquo;ll be using for jotting down quick unbacked findings and here&amp;rsquo;s few samples. I&amp;rsquo;m always on look out for new music. Already have few thousand songs here and there, but too much is not enough! There are now two online music services available: Yahoo&amp;rsquo; Launch and Lycos&amp;rsquo; Rhapsody (it&amp;rsquo;s playing &amp;ldquo;Pure Moods III&amp;rdquo; right now on my laptop). The Yahoo Launch is free and it will sequence up the new music for you by looking at your likings and ratings. Very cool. It did correctly picked up many of my favorites from some of the sample ratings I gave to it. A relief for someone like me who have exhausted out of choices. It has tons of online free videos. That&amp;rsquo;s super cool because MTV sucks at showing music videos these days and I desperately needed some on-demand music video service. And here it goes! Saying that, however, Launch collection isn&amp;rsquo;t really very big - i.e. it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have 10s of thousands of songs - just few thousands. There steps in the Rhapsody. They charge $10/mo and you can listen online to their collection of some 10000 CDs. It&amp;rsquo;s like carrying that many CDs to your work or a hotel or Starbucks :-). You can even burn selected tracks to CD for $1/track. But there is no videos. Many of my favorites I found there: Matchbox 20, Lincoln Park, Enigma, Moby&amp;hellip; Some I didn&amp;rsquo;t found were Jewel, Enya and many others. So it&amp;rsquo;s kind of balanced collection but imagine, full CDs - right there waiting to get played! These days if anybody recommends me any album/artists I first listen on Rhapsody and they think about buying it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
