<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Site News | Shital Shah</title>
    <link>http://shital.com/category/site-news/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://shital.com/category/site-news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Site News</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>(C) Shital Shah. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2003 14:26:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://shital.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Site News</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/category/site-news/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Yahoo Group Membership</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/your-yahoo-group-membership/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2003 14:26:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/your-yahoo-group-membership/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Due to recent changes, your membership might have been messed up in Yahoo groups that I maintain. If you got unsubscribed and not getting any emails, please use following links to correct it: Group: &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/shital/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shital&lt;/a&gt; Group: &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/MyTechList/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MyTechList&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jun-July Photo Album</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/jun-july-2003-photo-album/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2003 05:25:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/jun-july-2003-photo-album/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This quick and small album could be viewed at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dotphoto.com/go.asp?l=sytel&amp;amp;AID=910803&amp;amp;Pres=Y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;dotPhoto&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll post it on my site when I stop being lazzzy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Version Of This Site Comming Soon</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/shitalshahweb-v3-coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2003 21:36:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/shitalshahweb-v3-coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The new look[s] and content is soon coming to replace my current web site. This new version will feature something called themed site - i.e. I can make my site look like anything I want in minutes! This concept is not new but as I wanted to take care of all small details, it took me 30 hours of heavy duty ASP.Net programming and couple of missed meals last weekend to accomplish this - in most ideal way I could think of. Thanks to all rain and cool air coming from my window - which kept me working long long hours. There will be change in content too. I&amp;rsquo;m planning to delete some of them. So just in case, you&amp;rsquo;d liked it, save it in your own machine before it disappears! Apart from that, I&amp;rsquo;ll be moving my blogs to my own blogging tool. These blogs are currently hosted on blogger.com and that thing SUCKS! They charge for their crappy blogging software and still 50% of the features I want are missing. I&amp;rsquo;m just tired of looking around for another blogging service and so I got to write my own - my next mission.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My New Photo Albums</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/my-new-photo-albums-mar-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2003 09:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/my-new-photo-albums-mar-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d become little lazy in putting up my photos since last many many months but now I just looked back and thought these ought to be out there or at least some of them! So here goes my Saturday night updating my photo albums! But in this blog I want to talk little about taking photographs. First, you do not need bulky pricey cameras. The good photos you capture entirely depends on the angle, moment and your judgment rather then technology embedded in camera (gee, and you still call me a geek!). Almost all photos in all of my albums so far were taken from mere 1 Mega pixel digital cameras which had all necessary functionalities but weren&amp;rsquo;t the high end ones (HP C20 and Sony DCR-100). The key to get good photographs is just to get out more. And every time. Make your will exceed the difficulties posed by weather or other circumstances. For example photos in my new album on Verrazano bridge were taken on one of the cold day in winter with chilling winds. I still remember my hands were frozen at the point of getting numb even after wearing gloves and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t hold my camera still! Yet in other album on Sun rising from behind the New York City it was even more brutal - I&amp;rsquo;d forgot my gloves! You won&amp;rsquo;t feel the chilling winds in those beautiful photos but it were there. If you ask why others don&amp;rsquo;t have these photos, it&amp;rsquo;s for simple reason: they weren&amp;rsquo;t out there. One more thing, you might want to avoid any retouching of your digital photographs unless you really want to do some modern artsy thing. The only thing I would allow on my photos is resize and 90 degree rotate. However tempting it might be, absolutely no enhancements of any type - the world deserves the truth the way you saw it! Finally I must thank the pool of positive feedback last year for these photographs but I guess I do not consider myself an artsy or even dedicated photographer. Infect much of the time I intentionally do not carry my camera or don&amp;rsquo;t take a snap even if I had one. You do loose capturing some magnificent views but you don&amp;rsquo;t loose moments :). My new photo albums can be &lt;a href=&#34;http://shital.com/p/category/photos/&#34;&gt;viewed from my site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Of Blog - How To Carry 10,000 CDs With You</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/first-of-blog-how-to-carry-10000-cds-with-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2002 23:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/first-of-blog-how-to-carry-10000-cds-with-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first blog&amp;hellip; wonder why didn&amp;rsquo;t started this already! First what&amp;rsquo;s Astrila? I can&amp;rsquo;t tell for sure but it probably means &amp;ldquo;sparkling snow in star light&amp;rdquo; in Eskimo&amp;rsquo;s language. Well some don&amp;rsquo;t agree however. I&amp;rsquo;ve my personal web site at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ShitalShah.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://www.ShitalShah.com&lt;/a&gt; - that&amp;rsquo;s my name Shital Shah. This blog I&amp;rsquo;ll be using for jotting down quick unbacked findings and here&amp;rsquo;s few samples. I&amp;rsquo;m always on look out for new music. Already have few thousand songs here and there, but too much is not enough! There are now two online music services available: Yahoo&amp;rsquo; Launch and Lycos&amp;rsquo; Rhapsody (it&amp;rsquo;s playing &amp;ldquo;Pure Moods III&amp;rdquo; right now on my laptop). The Yahoo Launch is free and it will sequence up the new music for you by looking at your likings and ratings. Very cool. It did correctly picked up many of my favorites from some of the sample ratings I gave to it. A relief for someone like me who have exhausted out of choices. It has tons of online free videos. That&amp;rsquo;s super cool because MTV sucks at showing music videos these days and I desperately needed some on-demand music video service. And here it goes! Saying that, however, Launch collection isn&amp;rsquo;t really very big - i.e. it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have 10s of thousands of songs - just few thousands. There steps in the Rhapsody. They charge $10/mo and you can listen online to their collection of some 10000 CDs. It&amp;rsquo;s like carrying that many CDs to your work or a hotel or Starbucks :-). You can even burn selected tracks to CD for $1/track. But there is no videos. Many of my favorites I found there: Matchbox 20, Lincoln Park, Enigma, Moby&amp;hellip; Some I didn&amp;rsquo;t found were Jewel, Enya and many others. So it&amp;rsquo;s kind of balanced collection but imagine, full CDs - right there waiting to get played! These days if anybody recommends me any album/artists I first listen on Rhapsody and they think about buying it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
