<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reading | Shital Shah</title>
    <link>http://shital.com/categories/reading/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://shital.com/categories/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Reading</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>(C) Shital Shah. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 May 2005 00:00:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://shital.com/img/shitalshah.jepg</url>
      <title>Reading</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/categories/reading/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Illustrated Brief History of Time, Updated and Expanded Edition</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/the-illustrated-brief-history-of-time-updated-and-expanded-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2005 00:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/the-illustrated-brief-history-of-time-updated-and-expanded-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2005/05/brief_hist_time.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2005/05/brief_hist_time.gif&#34; alt=&#34;book cover&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;134&#34; class=&#34;alignleft size-full wp-image-836&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a really engaging book. It will take you to the journey of just few microseconds after the big bang, the sequence of events for next few minutes and how everything came to existance. It&amp;rsquo;s not baseless as it may sound, there is tons of mathematics behind every conclusion. Even more engaging is the discussion why we should bother about this? The book is slim and probably the best in astrophysics ever written for a layman! &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0553103741/102-3263321-6040950&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;More on this book&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moon Lander : How We Developed the Apollo Lunar Module</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/moon-lander-how-we-developed-the-apollo-lunar-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2005 00:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/moon-lander-how-we-developed-the-apollo-lunar-module/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2005/05/moon_lander.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft size-full wp-image-841&#34; alt=&#34;book cover&#34; src=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2005/05/moon_lander.gif&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;149&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Book written by Thomas Kelly, Chief Engineer of LM itself. Also check out for the very cool DVD set called &amp;ldquo;From Earth To Moon&amp;rdquo;. This book is whole of Part 5 in DVD2. &lt;a class=&#34;ActiveLink&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/156098998X/102-3263321-6040950&#34; target=&#34;new&#34;&gt;More on this book&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turn Left at Orion: A Hundred Night Sky Objects to See in a Small Telescope--and How to Find Them</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/turn-left-at-orion-a-hundred-night-sky-objects-to-see-in-a-small-telescope-and-how-to-find-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2005 00:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/turn-left-at-orion-a-hundred-night-sky-objects-to-see-in-a-small-telescope-and-how-to-find-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2005/05/turn_left_orion.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft size-full wp-image-842&#34; alt=&#34;book cover&#34; src=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2005/05/turn_left_orion.gif&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;130&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The best book to start out for amature astronomy. There&amp;rsquo;s heavens up there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;ActiveLink&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0521781906&#34; target=&#34;new&#34;&gt;More on this book&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HAL&#39;s Legacy: 2001&#39;s Computer as Dream and Reality</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/hals-legacy-2001s-computer-as-dream-and-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2005 00:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/hals-legacy-2001s-computer-as-dream-and-reality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2005/05/hals_legacy.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2005/05/hals_legacy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;book cover&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;109&#34; class=&#34;alignleft size-full wp-image-838&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;So you have seen the movie &amp;ldquo;2001: The Space Odyssey&amp;rdquo; and thought for a while it&amp;rsquo;s 2001 already and why we are not there? Well, important question would be where we are and still how far to go. This book is the essays written by few of the top experts in computer industry outlining what are the extremes achieved so far. Well, after few chapters it becomes quite boring though…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0262692112/102-3263321-6040950&#34; target=&#34;new&#34;&gt;More on this book&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Book of Business Breakthroughs: Lessons from the 20 Greatest Business Decisions Ever Made</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/the-ultimate-book-of-business-breakthroughs-lessons-from-the-20-greatest-business-decisions-ever-made/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2005 00:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/the-ultimate-book-of-business-breakthroughs-lessons-from-the-20-greatest-business-decisions-ever-made/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2005/05/buss_breakthroughs.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2005/05/buss_breakthroughs.gif&#34; alt=&#34;buss_breakthroughs&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; class=&#34;alignleft size-full wp-image-837&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only way to make your dreams come true, to do things your way and have more than enough money - it to have your own business! This book is about 20 companies who made certain critical decisions and came out to be the top and way ahead of competitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1841120286&#34; target=&#34;new&#34;&gt;More on this book&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey Through Genius : The Great Theorems of Mathematics</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/journey-through-genius-the-great-theorems-of-mathematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2005 00:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/journey-through-genius-the-great-theorems-of-mathematics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2005/05/journey_genius.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2005/05/journey_genius.gif&#34; alt=&#34;journey_genius&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;155&#34; class=&#34;alignleft size-full wp-image-840&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots and lots of books written on mathematics claiming to target mass audience and containing none to minimal &amp;ldquo;mathematics&amp;rdquo;. You read these kind out of books and when you turn last page, you ask yourself what was really going on all the way? Well this book is different and if you ask me, it&amp;rsquo;s the best book on mathematics I&amp;rsquo;ve came across. It&amp;rsquo;s collection of few not-too-obvious theorems derived from scratch with it&amp;rsquo;s histories and uses and stories. It&amp;rsquo;s the way math textbooks should have been written. And it&amp;rsquo;s so good, I hate to say I&amp;rsquo;ve found any other book that&amp;rsquo;s come even near to this one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;ActiveLink&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/014014739X/102-3263321-6040950&#34; target=&#34;new&#34;&gt;More on this book&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Networks And Learning Bayesian Networks</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/neural-networks-and-learning-bayesian-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2004 05:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/neural-networks-and-learning-bayesian-networks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are the two most interesting subjects for me right now. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0761914404/102-9310019-0481730&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;This book on Neural Networks&lt;/a&gt; is probably the best to take a dive in the field. This is truly the magnificent book that you can read like some thriller story (assuming you are not afraid of some mathematical depth) and look at the real working through cool numerical examples. Short but concise explanations might make this book deceptively tiny but it&amp;rsquo;s sure the best introduction in this field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0130125342/102-9310019-0481730&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Learning Bayesian Networks&lt;/a&gt; is little dry but has solid examples and it promises answers to some of the puzzling questions that had been playing around in my mind while thinking about my own correlation algorithm. So it’s still an interesting read. This book you can probably read more comfortably if you are already familiar with &lt;a href=&#34;http://shital.com/p/get-yourself-some-bayes/&#34;&gt;Bayesian probabilities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sticky Chapter</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/sticky-chapter-brief-history-of-time-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2003 05:35:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/sticky-chapter-brief-history-of-time-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m stuck on Chaper 8 of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0553103741/102-3263321-6040950&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Brief History Of Time&lt;/a&gt; again. This is happening for the 3rd time. Everytime I read this book I get until this chapter and then eventually give up. This time I tried to track down the fault and realized this chapter is so much unorganized and has apparently unrelated thoughts, though interesting - which keeps me coming back to it. Okay&amp;hellip; let&amp;rsquo;s start again. Shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language Of Flowers</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/language-of-flowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2003 14:21:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/language-of-flowers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found a little booklet today titled &amp;ldquo;The Secret Language Of Flowers&amp;rdquo; by Rachel Ibarra explaining nicely what each flower means when you give it to someone. I&amp;rsquo;ve to confess, I&amp;rsquo;m not good at it and so have to depend on the lady at the check-out counter to make sure I don&amp;rsquo;t buy flowers for my boss which would mean &amp;ldquo;secret love&amp;rdquo; on her birthday :). I can&amp;rsquo;t find this book on Amazon or B&amp;amp;N so you have to go to your nearest grocery store such as Pathmark to get it. Alternatively there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thegardener.btinternet.co.uk/flowerlanguage.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this nice web page for this&lt;/a&gt; but without pictures chances of screw up is high!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Books</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/new-books-july-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2003 15:33:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/new-books-july-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m running out of books to read so I was on shopping spree at Amazon. Just picked up few books from my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/o/registry/2MMKTBONOFNVX&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wish List&lt;/a&gt; and then few books from my favorite authors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/051722108X/104-8582029-6926363&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Adventures of Tom Sawyer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0691099839/104-8582029-6926363&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gamma: Exploring Euler&amp;rsquo;s Constant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0316919160/104-8582029-6926363&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How Would You Move Mount Fuji? Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Cult of the Puzzle - How the World&amp;rsquo;s Smartest Company Selects the Most Creative Thinkers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0679743898/104-8582029-6926363&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Artificial Life: A Report from the Frontier Where Computers Meet Biology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0066620724/104-8582029-6926363&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Just for Fun: The Story of an Accidental Revolutionary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0060936509/104-8582029-6926363&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Best American Science Writing 2002&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Find - Complications By Atul Gowande</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/book-find-complications-by-atul-gowande/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2002 07:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/book-find-complications-by-atul-gowande/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This book I&amp;rsquo;d bought for my brother who is a doc by profession but unfortunately he has to now wait until I finish reading it. While the lingo of biological sciences usually tends to scare us, I&amp;rsquo;d always a fascination for doctor&amp;rsquo;s life and this book is about it and more. The author takes you in the real stories that happened in his career as a trainee surgeon with a style that might put a fiction writer to a shame. The real beauty, however, is in the microscopic details. The philosophies involved in medical profession is embedded here with the wit and sharpness of a logician and that&amp;rsquo;s another stronger side of this book. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0805063196/002-0203858-4756001&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Click here to have a look&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Books &lt;i&gt;About&lt;/i&gt; Programmers</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/some-books-about-programmers-2002/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2002 18:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/some-books-about-programmers-2002/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theweblogreview.com/review.php?id=2042&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;couple of reviews&lt;/a&gt; of my blogs at Weblog Review. Looks it aren&amp;rsquo;t all that bad after all :). This one is about the few cool books that I came across on programmer&amp;rsquo;s life, passions, dreams and thoughts. To tell you the truth, all of them has kept me awake until early mornings since past few months. If you are hard core programmer from the roots, you are in for the real treat! Be hold! The first on the list is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0141000511/002-0203858-4756001&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hackers&lt;/a&gt;. No, it isn&amp;rsquo;t about breaking illegally in to some computer system. It&amp;rsquo;s about the very first computer programmers who put their foot steps in to this new world - like a little curious girl entering in the wild magical world of fairy tales. But more than the technicality, the thing that will touch you, cut your skin and swirl through your soul is the stories of passion that these people had - stories that are now permanently carved in to every page of this little book. A wonderful work. After coming from work, I would usually tell myself that I&amp;rsquo;m gonna read couple pages and then I&amp;rsquo;ll got to sleep and almost always I ended up staying awake until 5 in the morning with my face little tired of all those smirks that passed by. I can see myself and my career like a mirror in this book. It&amp;rsquo;s like reading stories of your ancestors and identifying yourself - or more like explaining yourself why the way you are. I believe you don&amp;rsquo;t have to be techie to read this book - it&amp;rsquo;s more a testament than a technology on the heights of human passion that this profession somehow inherently needs you to posses. Second on the list is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0887306292/002-0203858-4756001&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hard Drive&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s about Bill Gates and building of Microsoft during early years (1975-1990). Well, I never really cared about this (this is my first book on the subject) and my perception of Bill Gates was pretty much like &amp;ldquo;smart business man who got super lucky&amp;rdquo;. Above book, Hackers, however changed all that. I was actually shocked to know that Bill Gates is &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; just another hacker - a hard core geek - just like many of others around. And I was just hooked up in to those stories - probably some of the coolest one in Software industry. Author has like picked up all tiny hilarious interesting details. I used to find myself spending hours in conversations about bits from this book and spreading laughs. You just can&amp;rsquo;t put it down! Last one and which I haven&amp;rsquo;t finished yet (I&amp;rsquo;m kind of saving it from reading it entirely) is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0029356717/002-0203858-4756001&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Show-Stoppers&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s hilarious. detailed, passionate and revealing inside stories of one of the biggest software project ever under taken. After reading the Hard Drive I just can&amp;rsquo;t get enough to know about the Microsoft. This book takes from where Hard Drive leaves - the after 1990 era. And this one is very detailed and that&amp;rsquo;s why it&amp;rsquo;s more fun to read. I almost felt like a team member who lived in the NT team - feeling same pressure, finding ways to curse, getting ashamed for blunders and rejoicing for the final target that would be achieved. If you happen to live in programming world, this book is an &lt;em&gt;absolute must&lt;/em&gt; Don&amp;rsquo;t Miss. For others, take it as an optional.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Read Music : Reading Music Made Simple</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/how-to-read-music-reading-music-made-simple/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/how-to-read-music-reading-music-made-simple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2005/05/how_read_music.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2005/05/how_read_music.gif&#34; alt=&#34;how_read_music&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;128&#34; class=&#34;alignleft size-full wp-image-839&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were amazed by people interpreting those beautiful musical symbols or wanted to learn piano, this is for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0312241593&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;More on this book..&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
