<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geekery | Shital Shah</title>
    <link>http://shital.com/category/geekery/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://shital.com/category/geekery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Geekery</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>(C) Shital Shah. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2012 07:14:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://shital.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Geekery</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/category/geekery/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Groups, Places and Collectives for Makers in Seattle Area</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/groups-places-and-collectives-for-makers-in-seattle-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2012 07:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/groups-places-and-collectives-for-makers-in-seattle-area/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We went to Mini Makers Faire in Seattle today and one of most surprising thing I learned was how abundant are the local&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;resources for hackers and makers! Reminded me of geek fairy tales of &lt;a href= &#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homebrew\_Computer\_Club&#34;&gt;Homebrew Computer Club&lt;/a&gt; that you often hear. Here are some of the things&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you want to check out if you are interested in making stuff and live in Seattle area:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://metrixcreatespace.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Metrix Create: Space&lt;/a&gt; – I think this was the coolest thing I came to know about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have a shop with everything from sewing machine to electronics. They run lots of interesting &lt;a href= &#34;http://wiki.metrixcreatespace.com/workshops&#34;&gt;workshops &amp;amp; classes&lt;/a&gt;. It’s your neighborhood fab lab!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.makeseattle.net&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Make Seattle Meetup Group&lt;/a&gt; – Regular meet ups for Arduino/electronics makers and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;learners to exchange ideas and get help on your projects&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wstoollibrary.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;West Seattle Tools Library&lt;/a&gt; – I thought this was the coolest concept. They have a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;collection of 1500 tools that you can checkout for your projects. Just look at their &lt;a href= &#34;http://wstoollibrary.org/category/education/tool-of-the-week/&#34;&gt;tool of the week&lt;/a&gt; series. There is also &lt;a href= &#34;http://wsfixers.org/&#34;&gt;Fixers Collective&lt;/a&gt; who meet up at Tools Library and would be happy to fix your broken stuff or just&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tinker around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Xbot Robotics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workshop Space]&lt;a href=&#34;http://xbotrobotics.org/index.php?option=com_content&amp;amp;view=article&amp;amp;id=51&amp;amp;Itemid=58&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt; – They provide you space to work on your projects along with access to almost everything you need such as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;power tools, soldering stations, oscilloscopes, electronics components, drill presses, sand blasters, table saws, sanders,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;grinders!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were quite a few of cool things we saw there everything from [The&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brain Machine]&lt;a href=&#34;http://ladyada.net/make/brain/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.logos-electro.com/zigduino/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Zigduino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href= &#34;http://weekendamerica.publicradio.org/display/web/2008/06/11/montys_robot/&#34;&gt;Lifesuit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href= &#34;http://www.marginallyclever.com/category/drawbot-my-creations/&#34;&gt;Drawbots&lt;/a&gt;, to &lt;a href= &#34;http://www.instructables.com/id/The-Most-Useless-Machine/&#34;&gt;The Most Useless Machine Ever&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also jotted down the next classes I want to do at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pratt.org/classes.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Pratt&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href= &#34;http://www.allmetalarts.org/classes/&#34;&gt;All Metal Arts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Left Handed For Mouse</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/go-left-handed-for-mouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2005 21:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/go-left-handed-for-mouse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I observed how unequally I use my right and left hands. It’s not because I don’t type with my both hands but it’s because I use only the right hand in maneuvering and clicking the mouse. Considering the number of clicks I make per day, this huge lack of load-balancing is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lifehacker.com/software/life-hacks/how-to-avoid-carpal-tunnel-syndrome-101679.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;terrible&lt;/a&gt;! So I switched the mouse on left hand and it’s been great (reminds me the first time I hold the mouse) except that my mouse is curved so it’s comfortable only on right hand. I guess I’m gonna get a new mouse which is left+right handed, wireless (easy to switch hands), optical and at least 5 buttons. Don’t forget to reverse the mouse buttons in control panel! This is really fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, besides those &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ergonomics.com.au/howtosit.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;sitting posture tips&lt;/a&gt;, I think the one factor that strongly affects your creativity at work is how far you can look from your desk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DVD-Audio Format</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/dvd-audio-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 21:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/dvd-audio-format/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&#34;http://shital.com/p/blue-man-group-and-polyphonic-spree/&#34;&gt;recent quest&lt;/a&gt; to find new music, I bumped in to brand new &lt;a href=&#34;http://searchstorage.techtarget.com/sDefinition/0,,sid5_gci510035,00.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DVD-A format&lt;/a&gt; on which many &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/browse/-/574074/102-8083421-0521740&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;new demanding music albums&lt;/a&gt; are being delivered. It appears that this is definitely the next generation of music quality but there is very little or no information on many of its aspects. Here I&amp;rsquo;ll try to summarize what I found so far:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This format is capable of delivering very high quality multi-channel surround sound on your home theater system. The DVD-A format is entirely different than usual &lt;a href=&#34;http://home.clear.net.nz/pages/adbarr/page1.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dolby Digital or DTS&lt;/a&gt; which is used for DVD movies. The quality that could be delivered using DVD-A is superior than Dolby Digital or DTS. If you look in to your DVD disk in Windows Explorer, you will find that there are two folders: Audio_TS and Video_TS. So far, only Video_TS folder was used to put all the movie files on DVDs because industry wasn&amp;rsquo;t settled on standards for DVD-A format. Recently standards have been finalized and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/browse/-/574074&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;loads of new music albums&lt;/a&gt; are now being released in this format. They have content inside Audio_TS folder which contains DVD-A audio tracks in files with extension .aob. Because its brand new format, you need &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digitalaudioguide.com/dareview/players.htm#da%20%28DVD-Audio%29%20Players&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;newer DVD players&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.soundblaster.com/products/Audigy2ZS_platinum_pro/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;sound cards&lt;/a&gt; to play it. However because most people aren&amp;rsquo;t going to upgrade their DVD players soon, these audio DVDs supply same sound tracks in Video_TS folder encoded in usual Dolby Digital or DTS which all players knows how to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now say you buy an audio album on DVD disc. Obviously you can&amp;rsquo;t play it on car stereo or your portable MP3 players because it’s a DVD disc rather than normal audio CD. Or you might want to take backup of your DVD-A disc as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windows/windowsmedia/domorewith/sursoshowcase.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;WMA Pro&lt;/a&gt; files on your PC whcih allows 7.1 surround sound and playback. So what you do? You need to convert DVD disc in to normal Audio disc or rip tracks to MP3s. Unfortunately this isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. The DVD-A format employs &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.extremetech.com/article2/0,1558,1638228,00.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;higher level of encryption&lt;/a&gt; than usual DVDs. The DVD videos (stored in .vob files) employs copy protection scheme called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.extremetech.com/article2/0,1558,1638226,00.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CSS&lt;/a&gt; which can be broken in to very easily using DeCSS or even more friendly &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dvddecrypter.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DVD Decryptor&lt;/a&gt;. But &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digitalaudioguide.com/faq/dvd-audio/faq_intro.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DVD-A format&lt;/a&gt; which was developed later has learned lesson from this hack and currently there is no known way to decrypt .aob files which contains DVD-A audio tacks. That means you can&amp;rsquo;t rip MP3s out of AOB files. Your only way out is to rip off from slightly lower quality Dolby/DTS formatted tracks. The most reliable and easy to use software to do this is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.castudio.org/dvdaudioextractor/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DVD Audio Extractor&lt;/a&gt;. Fortunately many DVD-A albums also provides &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.videohelp.com/forum/archive/t140530.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LPCM&lt;/a&gt; version of tracks along with AC3 (i.e. Dolby Digital)/DTS format. So to burn normal audio CDs or MP3s you might want to choose LPCM version. If DVD-A disc &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/B000051S65/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain LPCM tracks&lt;/a&gt;, than you are out of luck. The down-mix/demux process employed by most software to convert surround sound from AC3/DTS to plain stereo format doesn&amp;rsquo;t produce same quality as commercially available stereo tracks. Though you can try &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.trevormarshall.com/byte_articles/byte7.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;some equations&lt;/a&gt; to combine 5.1 channels in to stereo using SoftEncode etc and usually DTS works better than AC3.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continual Survival Of SharpReader</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/continual-survival-of-sharpreader/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2004 20:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/continual-survival-of-sharpreader/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sharpreader.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SharpReader&lt;/a&gt; to read &lt;a href=&#34;http://shital.com/post-files/2004/09/sharpreader.zip&#34;&gt;my news (opml zip)&lt;/a&gt;. This is a small free app that has amazingly survived like an unevolving little insect in an environment where new species with more beef keeps coming. But this thing is still not extinct. I run around to look for an option with more features and end up at using SharpReader again and again. I&amp;rsquo;m though more interested that it dies away for one reason - the author isn&amp;rsquo;t publishing source code and at the same time he doesn&amp;rsquo;t have time to improve it by himself. It has pretty limited feature set but its designed so that its just barely enough to keep you alive. I tried to switch to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rssbandit.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RSS BandIt&lt;/a&gt; just to find that its fat feature list had missed some hearty points. Yesterday I looked at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.com/omea/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Omega Reader&lt;/a&gt; and was very excited that finally this will call for an end of SharpReader - just to find that its &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.com/omea/features/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;super-fat features&lt;/a&gt; comes with same numbers of bugs. So I&amp;rsquo;m still continue to live with SharpReader virus. Its an example how to design your programs so that your users wouldn&amp;rsquo;t like it and at the same time can&amp;rsquo;t give it up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool Pocket PC Stuff</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/cool-pocket-pc-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2003 06:13:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/cool-pocket-pc-stuff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you got this thingy and don&amp;rsquo;t know what to do with it besides storing phone numbers and birthdays, well, here&amp;rsquo;s some &amp;ldquo;secrets&amp;rdquo; I came across after my first night with it 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pocketgear.com/software_detail.asp?id=3004&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sexual Positions 1.0&lt;/a&gt; - Of course, this has to be the first to grab :). No freaky stuff in this one and it&amp;rsquo;s legally free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pocketgear.com/software_detail.asp?id=3176&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Pocket Bartender&lt;/a&gt; - It&amp;rsquo;s so convenient to handover your Pocket PC to bartender and ask her to make that drink that no one else has ever heard of!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bisque.com/Products/TheSkyPE/TheSkyPE.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TheSky Pocket Edition&lt;/a&gt; - This is probably the best and most popular in it&amp;rsquo;s category. Think about coming out of your car, tap on your Pocket PC to see real-time sky map and know the name of that star you been wondering about in the middle of nowhere. If you had good telescope, you can even plug-in your pocket pc in to it and control it with pen taps! Other such programs include &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nomadelectronics.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Pocket Stars&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stellarmetrics.com/Software/pu2000.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Pocket Universe&lt;/a&gt;. The bad thing about TheSky is that there is no trial edition available but I&amp;rsquo;ve heard that you can make a copy in someway if someone else has it. Don&amp;rsquo;t ask how!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://home.comcast.net/~jonsachs/#Ephemeris%201.0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ephemeris&lt;/a&gt; - This is cool little app to show moon phase, sun/moon rise times etc. Helpful if you were like me who won&amp;rsquo;t mind not sleeping additional one hour to see sun rise!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pdawin.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TV Remote Controller&lt;/a&gt; - I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to make this work but the basic idea is that you are sitting in the bar and suddenly TV channel gets changed to Star Trek from some stupid sports game and no one knows how did that happened.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alfcen.com/pocket/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Taiyoukei&lt;/a&gt; - This is nice set created by a Japanese guy for astronomy. Taiyoukei meaning &amp;ldquo;solar system&amp;rdquo;, for example, can tell you which planets are up in the sky right now among many other stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EBooks - There are several free (the one on Kazza may not count) ebooks available which you can read on Pocket PC during your bus trips to New York. Special fun are kids books: Alice in the wonderland, Encarta Pocket Dictionary, Adventure of Tom Sawyer and Julius Verne.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from these cool stuff, Pocket PC as an operating system totally sucks. How one can even think of making it and selling it? There&amp;rsquo;s lots of scope here to make additions to this crappy operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Google Toolbar</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/new-google-toolbar-jun-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2003 18:10:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/new-google-toolbar-jun-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://toolbar.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Google Toolbar&lt;/a&gt; is released and it&amp;rsquo;s even more cooler. It now has Popup blocker plus blogging support. I just blogged this straight from the toolbar!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yahoo! Launch Getting Better</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/yahoo-launch-getting-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2003 15:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/yahoo-launch-getting-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My favorite online music service Rhapsody is not working for me these days. They &lt;em&gt;removed&lt;/em&gt; entire Linkin Park collection, few albums from Kid Rock and God knows what more. So I&amp;rsquo;m back to my old favorite Yahoo! Launch. They have gotten better with more selection, many more videos and more features. The best thing is, ofcourse, you can tell it what you liked and it will select more your kinda music rather then purely random songs. And it&amp;rsquo;s totally free! You can &lt;a href=&#34;http://launch.yahoo.com/lc/?rt=0&amp;amp;rp1=0&amp;amp;rp2=1214708279&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;listen to my own customized radio station&lt;/a&gt; which I&amp;rsquo;m listening to right now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Worlds With POV-Ray</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/virtual-worlds-with-pov-ray-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2003 04:14:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/virtual-worlds-with-pov-ray-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2003/06/testground.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2003/06/testground-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;testground&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; class=&#34;alignleft size-medium wp-image-1099&#34; srcset=&#34;http://shitalshah.com/ShitalShahWP/wp-content/uploads/2003/06/testground-300x225.jpg 300w, http://shitalshah.com/ShitalShahWP/wp-content/uploads/2003/06/testground.jpg 512w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.povray.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;POV-Ray&lt;/a&gt; is the 3D graphic software which allows you to create 3D world with lightings, reflections, shadows, color gradients, materials, textures and so on. I&amp;rsquo;d read about it about 5 years ago and almost ignored it - until just few days back I decided to gave it a whirl one more time (I think it was a sudden urge to create some 3D graphics). Just after a quick simple installation and spending 15 minutes on beginner&amp;rsquo;s tutorial, I was totally in to it. Just a couple of hours more and I&amp;rsquo;d &lt;a href=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2003/06/testground.jpg&#34;&gt;my very first 3D image which is cool enough to show off&lt;/a&gt;. By the time night fall, I already had an AVI movie with a virtual walkthrough in my 3D world (by making camera move along a specified trajectory). This thing is addictive and it rocks. I can now calculate 3D coordinates and linear transformations in my head! The scripting language it uses is C like and very intuitive. Sure there were many other ray tracing programs including 3D Studio but this open source free program is much more &amp;ldquo;programmer oriented&amp;rdquo; rather then &amp;ldquo;artist oriented&amp;rdquo;. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.irtc.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Internet Ray Tracing Competition&lt;/a&gt; for some truly mind blowing virtual images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sytelus/PlayingWithPovRay&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Source code for my above first image is now at Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;github-widget&#34; data-repo=&#34;sytelus/PlayingWithPovRay&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Better Giving</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/the-better-giving-for-relatives-abroad-2002/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2002 07:09:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/the-better-giving-for-relatives-abroad-2002/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A year ago it took me around 6 months before I felt it was the perfect gift to give it to my cousins. But the trouble was that by the time they received it they got confused whether it was for last year&amp;rsquo;s occasion or coming year&amp;rsquo;s! It&amp;rsquo;s an art to find a gift that&amp;rsquo;s unique, hard to find, memorable and the one matching with person&amp;rsquo;s personality and need. Here are some of those tips and places that I came across over time to help you out this holiday season. 1. The premier destination to get the unique gift idea is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.surprise.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;surprise.com&lt;/a&gt;. A must visit if you are still in the complete darkness. 2. Check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sytelus/Bookmarks&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;my collection of gift links&lt;/a&gt;. You will find things ranging from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.drugstore.com/qxp69153_333181_sespider/kama_sutra/weekender_kit.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kamasutra weekender kit&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://stardate.utexas.edu/giftshop/store.tpl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Astronomy&amp;rsquo;s cool gift ideas&lt;/a&gt;. 3. To find out what&amp;rsquo;s latest and coolest, check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sciam.com/article.cfm?&amp;amp;articleID=00062C10-684A-1DDE-A838809EC588F2D7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Scientific American&amp;rsquo;s Top SciTech Gifts of 2002&lt;/a&gt;. This one is a real good contemporary compilation. 4. If you still didn&amp;rsquo;t found you were looking for, view &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sytelus/Bookmarks&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;my collection of shopping links&lt;/a&gt;. Specially check for Diversity Stores section. 5. Instead of giving gifts to someone who already has too much, you might want to ask them if it&amp;rsquo;s ok to give some donations to non-profit organizations instead of giving them yet another gift that would be anyway useless to them. Click here for some &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sytelus/Bookmarks&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;charity organizations in my links collection&lt;/a&gt;. 6. Finally here are my personal favorites and non-favorites for this year: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wizcomtech.com/products2/quicktionary2.php3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Quicktionary&lt;/a&gt;, Book light (both are perfect if a person is an avid reader), external hard drive (perfect for heavy laptop users because they always run out of space), &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.getfeetwet.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;handheld GPS&lt;/a&gt; (for outdoor person), &lt;a href=&#34;http://mindstorms.lego.com/eng/default.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lego Mindstorm robot kit&lt;/a&gt; (absolute perfect gift for kids), DVD/MP3 players, HP49 calc (perfect for mathematicians), &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ehobbies.com/radio-control-airplanes.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;model air plane kit&lt;/a&gt; (prefer unassembled ones). And now the things that sucks as gifts: fragrances, cloths, pocket PCs and palms, organizers, CD players, pocket MP3 players, RC cars, PS2. These gifts totally suck. Finally it&amp;rsquo;s not necessary to go overboard. Infect being a follower of &amp;lsquo;Grinch philosophy&amp;rsquo; I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to hate all give and take of gifts. May be it&amp;rsquo;s just enough to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sytelus/Bookmarks&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;send a web card&lt;/a&gt; with few clicks to let someone know that you still remember.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Get To Sleep Faster</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/how-to-get-to-sleep-faster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2002 06:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/how-to-get-to-sleep-faster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not submitting ourselves to sleep is a problem for many of us. Here&amp;rsquo;s few of the ideas that I found works getting little closer to your dreams 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The thing that almost always worked for me is to read real complex book filled with poorly proven math equations and undecipherable physics text (or some translated ones). It quickly drains out all extra energies and puts you in nice sleep (no pun intended)!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn on your air conditioner. The heat won&amp;rsquo;t let you die. The colder environment slows down body functions, helps to dry down the energy levels and drives you towards the kind of &amp;ldquo;stasis&amp;rdquo;. Note that you should never sleep without warm comforter/duvets in this case (even if this looks contradictory)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new recent find that has also worked well: drink glass of warm milk before going to sleep! Well, actually it&amp;rsquo;s from all-wise &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.startrek.com/library/individ.asp?ID=112466&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Guineen&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s character in Star Trek TNG. No wonder it works 🙂&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The last one is to put on the run of classical music on very low volume. It isn&amp;rsquo;t very effective but it&amp;rsquo;s cool!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Blog</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/how-to-blog-on-blogger-com-2002/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2002 04:34:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/how-to-blog-on-blogger-com-2002/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just finished making this blog page! Wow. It took exactly 5 hours. When I started, I was going to program this whole stuff by myself and almost on the verge of firing VS.Net. And then I saw this site Blogger.com. As per the 10 commandments of programming world, never spend time in writing programs which has been already done and which are reusable. And this site was great. I created a template so that user will see blogs as integral part of my site. No fuzz. Though I&amp;rsquo;d to pay $15 to remove ads. Other complains include lack of ability to post comments and no built in search engine. But otherwise, I nearly saved atleast 3 days worth of coding. I really wonder why I&amp;rsquo;ve started so late&amp;hellip; so many good things will now remain un-blogged&amp;hellip; lol.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
