<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life TODO | Shital Shah</title>
    <link>http://shitalshah.com/categories/life-todo/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://shitalshah.com/categories/life-todo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Life TODO</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>(C) Shital Shah. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2005 00:00:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://shitalshah.com/img/shitalshah.jepg</url>
      <title>Life TODO</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/categories/life-todo/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heavens Above</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/heavens-above/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2005 00:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/heavens-above/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that you have lived so many years, each having so many days, there&amp;rsquo;s question: How many times you have stood up, raised your head, seen the stars and felt nothing? Well, think twice. You&amp;rsquo;d just popped up your head out of your small tiny ridiculously insignificant world in to something that&amp;rsquo;s stunningly vast and breathtakingly beautiful. Astronomy has been a favorite passion for few of the us fortunate beings since ages and the lesser beings now need not left behind. While I&amp;rsquo;m still writing the page for plain beginners, here are the things you can do right how:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star parties is a gathering of few crazy people who wants to do all night long sky watching and help others out in knowing it better! &lt;a href=&#34;http://skyandtelescope.com/resources/calendar/&#34; title=&#34;Sky and Telescope magazine&#39;s Star Party calender&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Check out the events happening in your area&lt;/a&gt; and give yourself a go!.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy a book called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0521781906/qid=1018242805/sr=1-1/ref=sr_1_1/104-6492949-7167901&#34; title=&#34;Amazon.com&#39;s page for book&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Turn Left at Orion&lt;/a&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s the coolest one I&amp;rsquo;ve found so far.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join the club, meet people and ask questions! &lt;a href=&#34;http://skyandtelescope.com/resources/organizations/&#34; title=&#34;Sky and Telescope&#39;s page for clubs directory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Click here to find the one near you&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy a telescope. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B00004SPCH/qid=1018242660/sr=1-4/ref=sr_1_4/104-6492949-7167901&#34; title=&#34;Amazon.com&#39;s page for telescope&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meade ETX-125EC&lt;/a&gt; is just powerful enough in price range of under $1000. There are many much cheaper and still just little less powerful also available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Astronomy has been favorite passion for few of the us fortunate beings since ages and the lesser beings now need not left behind. While I&amp;rsquo;m still writing the page for plain beginners, here are the things you can do right how: Star parties is a gathering of few crazy people who wants to do all night long sky watching and help others out in knowing it better! Check out the events happening in your area and give yourself a go!. Buy a book called Turn Left at Orion. That&amp;rsquo;s the coolest one I&amp;rsquo;ve found so far. Join the club, meet people and ask questions! Click here to find the one near you! Buy a telescope. Meade ETX-125EC is just powerful enough in price range of under $1000. There are many much cheaper and still just little less powerful also available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fly High</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/fly-high/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2002 00:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/fly-high/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Flying is nearly every human&amp;rsquo;s dream and unstoppable desire. And now it&amp;rsquo;s possible to get enroll in to private pilot licence program, stay in a budget ($120/lesson without discounts) and see how the world looks from the eyes of the clouds! If you are a &lt;a href=&#34;www.startrek.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Star-Trek&lt;/a&gt; fan, you already know what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about. So get your feet off the ground and prepare to give that baby a little spin! Check out for the small airports around your area where you can almost usually find a flight training schools which may allow you to take a test or just walk-in lesson. And don&amp;rsquo;t worry. You will be putting your hands on very small planes like Cessna 152 which is fun to fly but you can&amp;rsquo;t really hurt anybody, ofcourse except yourself :-).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In To The Bloom</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/in-to-the-bloom/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/in-to-the-bloom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spring is here and so the refreshing blooms! Take a closer look to nature&amp;rsquo;s refreshing beauty by knowing the trees better. Can you identify at least 5 tress you will meet on the roads? Which tree doesn&amp;rsquo;t loose their leaves in fall? Is male and female flowers separate for this one? That&amp;rsquo;s just few questions you might. Get the pocket book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/158238133X/qid=1018245256/sr=1-2/ref=sr_1_2/104-6492949-7167901&#34; title=&#34;Books on trees&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Trees : A Guide to Familiar American Trees&lt;/a&gt; . If you are leaving neat New York city, visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.centralpark.org/&#34; title=&#34;NYC&#39;s Central Park&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Central Park&lt;/a&gt; - An ultra cool place for hang out. If you live somewhere else, search for the botanical gardens in your area or move on to road trips to state parks. Also check out the books on identifying flowers at &lt;a href=&#34;http://amazon.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind The Notes</title>
      <link>http://shitalshah.com/p/behind-the-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2001 00:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shitalshah.com/p/behind-the-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Those strange music notations always made me curious. How is it possible &amp;ldquo;write&amp;rdquo; the music? Will I ever be able to read these notations and play a piece? Can I jot down the notes of GNR&amp;rsquo;s Sweet Child Of Mine while I hear it? I read that some of the masters never really played few of their creations - it was all in their minds and then in to paper! Check out the books to get you started: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0764551051/qid=1018245869/sr=8-1/ref=sr_8_7_1/104-6492949-7167901&#34; title=&#34;Amazon.com listing for Piano For Dummies&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Piano For Dummies&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/097075129X/qid=1018246096/sr=1-1/ref=sr_1_1/104-6492949-7167901&#34; title=&#34;Amazon.com listing for the book&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Basic Music Theory : How to Read, Write, and Understand Written Music&lt;/a&gt;{.ActiveClass}&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
