<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events | Shital Shah</title>
    <link>http://shital.com/category/events/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://shital.com/category/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Events</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>(C) Shital Shah. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2010 23:46:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://shital.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Events</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/category/events/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burning Man Tips for the First Timers</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/burning-man-tips-for-the-first-timers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2010 23:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/burning-man-tips-for-the-first-timers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is no substitute to reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.burningman.com/preparation/event_survival/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;official Survival Guide&lt;/a&gt; but it does leaves out many things. So instead of writing my detailed trip report I thought about all the mistakes I’d made and converting them to tips. Here it goes…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sun shelter (things that look like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rei.com/product/731380&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;REI Alcove&lt;/a&gt;) is absolutely essential if you just have a camping tent. I would however not recommend REI Alcove itself because it broke after withstanding 3 days of sandstorms. Obviously you also need &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rei.com/product/766564&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;nice camping chair&lt;/a&gt; to go with it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regular tent stacks are not very useful to secure tents on playa. I didn’t believed that and my tent almost came out in sandstorms. The correct way to secure tent in playa is using something called “&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.homedepot.com/h_d1/N-5yc1vZ1xh8/R-100323499/h_d2/ProductDisplay?langId=-1&amp;amp;storeId=10051&amp;amp;catalogId=10053&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;rebars&lt;/a&gt;”. You need 4 rebars for a regular camping tent, each 3” long and 1/2” wide. You need another 4 or 6 for sun shelter. Stores like Home Depot would cut the metal rod for you in these sizes. Of course, you will need big hammer as well to stack them (they don’t have pointy end). Finally, it’s a hazard to leave other end of these rusty metal rods open so you must stick a tennis ball or empty bottles on end of the rod that is sticking out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sandstorms!&lt;/strong&gt; In 2009 there were 3 full days of sandstorms. If you never seen one then here’s how it works: About 20-60 foot tall wall of sand that comes at you at anywhere between 10 miles to 40 miles an hour. The visibility typically drops to 5ft to 50ft and you see brownish sand everywhere around you. This can last for up to 8 hours straight. It actually looks cool and as a matter of fact I intentionally spent lots of time inside sandstorm taking photos (note: Many SLRs are not dust proof). Even on severe storm days almost everyone continued their activities as if it was normal weather. But they were prepared. Here’s what you need to be prepared:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to have sun glasses with minimum open space around lenses. I had &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rei.com/product/766496&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tifosi Ventoux&lt;/a&gt; and they worked kind of OK. A &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rei.com/search?cat=8000&amp;amp;cat=4500069&amp;amp;cat=4500650&amp;amp;hist=cat%2C4500069%3ASunglasses%5ecat%2C4500650%3ASunglass&amp;#43;Retainers&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;retainer&lt;/a&gt; is also essential not to loose them (remember there are no shops to buy extra pair).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mask for the nose and mouth. I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.buffwear.com/catalog/index.php?cPath=1_5&amp;amp;sort=2a&amp;amp;max=1000000&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Buff bandana&lt;/a&gt; so I can pull it up all the way to sunglasses. Next time I would also be using &lt;a href=&#34;http://solutions.3m.com/wps/portal/3M/en_US/Health/Safety/Products/Catalog/?PC_7_RJH9U5230GE3E02LES9MG812H2_nid=XKJJ787RSQbeF3RH7CD92Ngl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rei.com/product/769766&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.icanbreathe.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; mask so I can be absolutely worry free about staying longer out in dust storms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hat with cord and visor. This will allow you to walk heads down while visor protects your face. I used &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sundayafternoons.com/store/adventure-hats.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this hat&lt;/a&gt; and it’s absolutely the best hat I’ve ever owned. Added advantage of this hat is that it’s veil can be put in the direction of wind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a first timer I found that 4 nights provides a very good breadth and depth for the experience. The reason it’s perfect is because you have to carry less food and water, not worry too much about getting shower and you still get to see nearly everything that’s out there. I would strongly recommend against staying &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; than 3 nights.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a stop at Reno at least for a night before heading towards Black Rock City. Besides mini-Las Vegas style environment, you can also visit REI, Walmart and Walgreens to get the gear, water, grocery and so on. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.peppermillreno.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Pepermill Resort&lt;/a&gt; is where I stayed overnight because it’s cheapest awesome hotel in Reno.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A compass is very useful to have to get on the right street when coming back in the night far away from playa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have 3-season camping tent you are probably in trouble. These tents usually have mesh in the walls for ventilation and they have rain fly to protect against rain. This arrangement however is pretty useless to protect against sandstorms. On a typical stormy day I would get about half inch layer of sand inside my 3 season tent and I had to spend an hour every night cleaning things up. Make sure you have duct tapes and things to cover up. Everything outside tent should be tied to rebars so it doesn’t fly away with storms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weather at burning man is 110F+. It’s normally not possible to sleep inside the tent after 10 AM. It’s not unusual to stay up until 3 AM. Nights are cold and you will need a fleece jacket. I’d 30 degree rated &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rei.com/product/760252&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;bag&lt;/a&gt; which was bit warmer but worked fine. BTW, try to bring sleeping bag liner to avoid it getting sweaty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a first timer it might be hard to understand culture of gifts. For example, someone I don’t know at all would give me something and I would be confused if I should really take it. This can spoil the experience for the giver and the taker. Here’s how it works: If someone gives you a gift, take it with a smile without hesitation and give them a gift in return. It’s that simple. The only thing to remember is to bring bunch of gifts that you can easily carry around. Here are some of the examples of gifts: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.123stickers.com/index.asp?PageAction=Custom&amp;amp;ID=68&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Custom stickers&lt;/a&gt; with your favorite quotes, necklaces, bead jewelry, &lt;a href=&#34;http://glowproducts.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;things that glows&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/s/qid=1282811182/ref=sr_nr_seeall_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;keywords=zimbabwe%20dollars&amp;amp;rh=i%3Aaps%2Ck%3Azimbabwe%20dollars%2Ci%3Amisc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Trillion Dollars Notes&lt;/a&gt;, candies, custom printed postcards and so on. A single major mistake first timers make is not to bring gifts to give away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bicycles would be your savior. If you can’t bring from home then rent or steal from Reno. BRC is really huge and you would be lucky if you could walk just one street a day. Most events that I was interested usually were many miles apart and it’s impossible to make it on time without bicycle. Besides you really don’t want to get tired after walking 10 miles just to attend couple of events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As soon as you enter gate you will be handed a map and booklet of events. The map is easy to understand because of it’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://earth.burningman.com/brc/2009/map/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;semi-circle streets&lt;/a&gt;. Any location is specified by using hand of clock and name of the street. The 6 o’clock is the center while 2 o’clock and 10 o’clock are two ends of semi-circle. The street names are different every year depending on the theme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is NO assigned camping sites at Burning Man (except for theme camps). Normally all except outer two streets are occupied within first couple of days. When I arrived on Wednesday evening I decided to keep as much distance from outer road as possible because that’s where all the cars keep passing by. But I did not wanted to be too inside because the view of vast playa on the outer street is awesome. I also wanted to stay in middle so distance to get on any side is minimized. Always consider if your neighbors have enough space around their tent to put picnic table or chairs or grills or another car. The best space I found on Wednesday night was at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gigapan.org/gigapans/34311/snapshots/161246/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;7:15 and Kinship&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If someone asks you “which camp are you in?” then that usually means “what is the name of your camp?”. You can consult with your neighbor to decide on some name for group camp and put on the sign. You can also tell the location such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gigapan.org/gigapans/34311/snapshots/161246/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;7:15 &amp;amp; Kinship&lt;/a&gt; like other first timers do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The iPhone &amp;amp; AT&amp;amp;T did worked with full 4 bars at Black Rock City in 2009. It’s really really a good choice to turn it off and resist temptation to tweet/facebook for your entire stay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here’s one of the most disgusting part of my Burning Man experience: The place I choose to camp was up-winds in the path of potty patties. That means every time wind blew even a little it would smell really really bad. It was horrible. Fortunately I came to my tent only to sleep when smell was gone. It’s really worth to make sure you avoid such smelly spaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t wear jeans at Burning Man! Many places that do not allow jeans believe that they are too “casual” for them but at Burning Man you don’t want to wear jeans because they would be too “formal”! I wore my normal jeans on first night and felt so out of place and formal that it was embarrassing. If you must wear jeans then take your old jeans, paint them or tear them or whatever. Shorts are semi-casual options at Burning Man.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The list of events at Burning Man is overwhelming. You do not have to go crazy to attend as many events as possible and it’s best to chose no more than 3 events per day to attend. It’s good idea to reserve one day just sit back at your tent and look at vast playa in mild warm wind :).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cooking at Burning Man can get tricky because of sandstorms. I’d bought my camping stove which didn’t work out in storms. Fortunately more prepared folks did cooking in their camps and gave away lots of free food. I’d also bought some non-perishable stuff like bananas, milk powder, Sahale snacks, bars, chips and so on. One last option for food is to go back to town via bus or car but that might ruin your experience. Fortunately I did not had that option because I didn’t had car and I never found the bus. One good outcome was that I lost few pounds! Next time I might just buy or rent a grill because it work better in dust storms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I estimated 1.5 gallon of water per day per person and it worked out well for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can meet and greet your neighbors without feeling awkward. When you cook meal, offer some to them. Always have at least two gifts to give away to your two neighbors while departing. Example of gifts are some sketch you made while at Burning Man or other art work or a poem or your favorite book or some photo you took.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes, you do need &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rei.com/product/758050&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;kitchen sink&lt;/a&gt;! You will need it to brush teeth, wash hands etc. It’s not OK to spill water with soap on playa floor but if your sink is small and soap biodegradable then you would be ok to collect water in it and then go to outer street to flung it away&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most people do not shower at Burning Man (or so I think). There are few elaborate large camps that set up showers and some even offer them to others as well. But in general, don’t expect showers. Alternative is wet towel to wipe off of your body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many camps on inner circle serves free drinks to anyone who wants but you need to bring your own cup. It helps a lot if you have a cup with lid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a place everybody refers to as “The Temple”. It’s located beyond The Man and many first timers would even miss it because they usually don’t go beyond The Man (it’s a LONG walk too). The Temple is truly sacred in many aspects without being connected to even the concept of religion. It’s humbling and even moving to spend a day at the temple. The Temple burns on next day after The Man burns and more spectacularly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Burning Man usually has 35,000+ people which causes 2 to 4 hours of traffic jams while leaving. While it’s fun to see the parade of every RV ever made, the time with least traffic to leave Burning Man is on Saturday night after The Man burns. But the flip side is that you will miss even more spectacular burn of The Temple which is on Sunday night. Another flip side of leaving on Saturday night is that you run huge risk of falling sleep while driving. When I left on Saturday night I saw at least 3 accidents on the way and so I decided to just pull over and sleep anyway. For my next time, I would be leaving on Monday late afternoon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally here are &lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/sytelus1/BurningMan2009#5509703293720242962&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;pictures from my trip&lt;/a&gt; which hopefully would give some idea about what to expect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coolest New York Shows In Run</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/coolest-new-york-shows-in-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2004 22:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/coolest-new-york-shows-in-run/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are the some of the select broadway/off-broadway shows currently running in New York. Many of them ends soon. If you live in area, do check them out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theatermania.com/content/show.cfm/show/106244&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GoogleWhack&lt;/a&gt; - This small production comedy had been consistently sold out in UK and Australia. Even if it hadn&amp;rsquo;t been, its pretty geeky enough for not to check it out :). We will be going to this show tonight! Ends December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theatermania.com/content/show.cfm/show/104809&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forever Tango&lt;/a&gt; - Looks extremely cool. Seven couple who tango in their own styles from Argentine. Ends Nov 28.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theatermania.com/content/show.cfm/show/101919&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cookin&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; - A terrific show. Korean crew creates awesome beats and music from mere kitchen appliances besides other jaw dropping stuff in the show. Absolutely recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theatermania.com/content/show.cfm/show/132&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Blue Man Show&lt;/a&gt; - If you want to see just one off-Broadway show in New York, this would be it. We went to this one last December and its an awesomely creative show which you might enjoy every moment of it (and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have intermission). Its difficult to describe what this show is about but one can escape describing it by calling higher form of modern art, just like its music. The show that&amp;rsquo;s being currently running has new &amp;ldquo;material&amp;rdquo; though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slavasnowshow.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Slava&amp;rsquo;s Snow Show&lt;/a&gt; - While except for closing sequence it wasn&amp;rsquo;t ultra cool, it sure was different. One might think its kids show but when we went to see it, we hardly observed more than couple of kids in audience (and show was sold out).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.trans-siberian.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Trans-Siberian Orchestra&lt;/a&gt; - This is the most impressive, most awesome and the coolest live concert I&amp;rsquo;ve ever been too. To miss them in live concert would be practically a sin. With hundreds of colorful spotlights, and another few hundreds of freaking lasers, and some cool fireworks right on the stage and a band of more than 20 musicians and singers and with very diversified styles, they simply doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nycomedyfestival.com/new/lineup/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Steven Wright Comedy Show&lt;/a&gt; - For a long time I considered Steve Wright as the most gifted comedian I&amp;rsquo;d known. His ability to make up original random unrelated witty one-liners which he can keep throwing at you one after another for the entire length of show is amazing. He hasn&amp;rsquo;t doing many shows since last few years but finally New York Comedy Festival provides a chance to hear him live!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also as a side tip, many (but not all) broadway show tickets you can buy at heavily discounted prices by entering secret codes. Sources to check out for this are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theatermania.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TheaterMania.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.broadwaybox.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;BroadwayBox.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://entertainment-link.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;entertainment-link.com&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://faculty.rmwc.edu/theatre/Ticket%20Watch/Current.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NY Times TicketWatch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hackers Conference @ NYC Starts</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/hackers-conference-nyc-2004/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2004 16:57:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/hackers-conference-nyc-2004/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.the-fifth-hope.org/hoop/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Fifth HOPE conference&lt;/a&gt; featuring talks, workshops, movies and other events from several well known hackers including Steve Wozniak, Cult of Dead Cow, John Draper and so on is already started at NYC today (July 9, 2004). I&amp;rsquo;d read lot about many of these people dedicated to pure hacking in early years in the book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0141000511&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hackers&lt;/a&gt; and now its a chance to actually hear them! The conference has 70+ talks which itself is pretty long list even to browse through. Here are my picks from the list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bypassing Corporate Restrictions from the Inside -Saturday 2000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fifth HOPE Closing Ceremonies - Sunday 1900&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hack Nano - Friday 2000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hacking CDMA PRLs - Sunday 1300&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hacking More of the Invisible World - Friday 1200&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hacking the Grid - Saturday 1500&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An Introduction to Dissembler - Saturday 1330&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lockpicking - Saturday 1100&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phreaking In The Early Days - Saturday 1000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pirate Radio: Running a Station and Staying on the Air - Friday 2300&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday Keynote: Steve Wozniak - Saturday 1300&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social Engineering - Sunday 1600&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Urban Exploring: Hacking the Physical World - Sunday 1300&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wireless and WiFi: The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly - Friday 1300&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Venus Transit Tomorrow</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/venus-transit-2004-08-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2004 23:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/venus-transit-2004-08-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This one is not a spectacular but its interesting because it&amp;rsquo;s rare and because of history. Specifically, in old times (pre 1900s), people used this rare event to measure distance between Earth and Sun. Infect astronomers didn&amp;rsquo;t knew this distance from a long time, so they invented so-called &amp;ldquo;1 Astronomical Unit (AU)&amp;rdquo; when they want to refer to this distance. In old times, everything was measured relative to AU, for example Venus is 0.7AU away from Sun. Venus Transit helped to resole this. Plus it also helped to figure out Sun&amp;rsquo;s diameter. Now just out of curiosity, I thought, how would Venus transit could help in determining Sun-Earth distance and Sun&amp;rsquo;s diameter? Answer is simple enough: Have two people watched it from different latitudes on Earth, make a triangle, use simple trigonometry and you get the distance! &lt;a href=&#34;http://sunearth.gsfc.nasa.gov/sunearthday/2004/vt_view_observatories_2004.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nasa has put up a detailed explanation&lt;/a&gt; of little math in involved in this clever technique. Then This is, of course, still less accurate then modern ways of radars and satellites. Venus orbits around Sun in just 0.6 years. Then one would think why transits are so rare? Well, answer is, Venus&amp;rsquo;s orbit isn&amp;rsquo;t in the same plane as Earth, so it&amp;rsquo;s pretty rare for Sun-Venus-Earth to get in one straight line, usually every little over hundres years or so. Apart from that, this transit won&amp;rsquo;t visually appeal to most but if you had those special safe glasses to view sun eclipse, you might have a look between 11:05AM to 11:25AM on US East Coast on June 8, 2004. More info at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exploratorium.edu/venusEC/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Exploratorium&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.astronomy.no/venus080604.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;astronomy.no&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese New Year Festivities</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/chinese-new-year-festivities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2004 21:04:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/chinese-new-year-festivities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While my wife would be celebrating &lt;a href=&#34;http://chineseculture.about.com/library/weekly/topicsub1.htm?once=true&amp;&#34; target=&#34;new&#34;&gt;Chinese New Year&lt;/a&gt; on more native land of Hong Kong, there would be quite a few events happening in NEw York city. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://gonyc.about.com/cs/holidays/a/chinesenewyear.htm&#34; target=&#34;new&#34;&gt;big parade&lt;/a&gt; is on Sunday 25th in Chinatown with dragons and lions, all red and gold, along with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.taipei.org/even/newyearevent/chinesenewyear.html&#34; target=&#34;new&#34;&gt;other events&lt;/a&gt;. Chinatown-Online gives nice little &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chinatown-online.com/year/year.shtml&#34; target=&#34;new&#34;&gt;info on traditions of Chinese New Year&lt;/a&gt; and other festivities dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The major deal of New Year is, of course, lavish food festivities. There is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://ccbany.org/restaurant_list.html&#34; target=&#34;new&#34;&gt;suprisingly large number of restaurants&lt;/a&gt; in NYC which will be offering special New Year meals, but here are some select few places to get the Year of the Monkey off to a good start (Chanoodle is the most recommended):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chanoodle - (212) 349-1495 - 79 Mulberry Street (Canal Street), Chinatown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Congee - (212) 965-5028 - 98 Bowery (Near Hester Street)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dim Sum Go Go - (212) 732-0797 - 5 East Broadway (Chatham Square)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Funky Broome - (212) 941-8628 - 176 Mott Street (Broome Street)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joe&amp;rsquo;s Ginger - 212) 966-6613 - 113 Mott Street (Near Hester Street)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ping&amp;rsquo;s Seafood - (212) 602-9988 - 22 Mott Street (Near Mosco Street)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sunrise 27 - 212) 219-8498 - 27 Division Street (Near Market Street)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Courtesy: NYTimes)&lt;/em&gt; However my personal choice would be the Rainbow platter at Penang, the Malaysian restaurant on Rt. 10. Have a good new year! Sing Dan Fai Lok!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Venus with Crescent Moon</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/venus-with-crescent-moon-2004-2-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2004 01:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/venus-with-crescent-moon-2004-2-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you live on East Coast and if you looked in to West in last few hours you might have seen a real bright blob of light. It&amp;rsquo;s so bright and has &amp;ldquo;burning aura&amp;rdquo; (literally looks like flames) around it that I thought it will soon fall down as huge shooting star. So I just fired up my copy of TheSky software to see what&amp;rsquo;s going on and came out with some neat surprise. Well, this is Venus and for next month or so it&amp;rsquo;s gonna be visible long after sunsets and would stay pretty well above horizon (which is not very usual for Venus). With it&amp;rsquo;s current magnitude of -4.0 that&amp;rsquo;s way way too bright for normal night sky standards and it&amp;rsquo;s gonna be even more brighter. If you trace path of Venus, it seems Venus and Moon both comes really really close (almost touching) on 23nd Feb, 2004 at around 17:34 which also happens to be Sunset time! And the beauty of the whole scene during this Sunset is that it would be really nice crescent moon. So watch out and put this date and time on your calendar!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leonid Meteor Shower This Tuesday</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/leonid-meteor-shower-2003-11-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2003 17:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/leonid-meteor-shower-2003-11-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This event is slowing down every year and so for some people it would be a reason not to care and for others it would be a reason to care even more, because next year it will be more slower :). But it&amp;rsquo;s still nice to see shooting stars with some predictability. This year, the peak time on East coast would be on 19th November between 12:00 to 2:30AM which is little earlier then past years. But again my wishes have already came true this year so don&amp;rsquo;t have lots of wishes to make :). Nasa has &lt;a href=&#34;http://leonid.arc.nasa.gov/estimator.html&#34; target=&#34;new&#34;&gt;really cool graphical estimator&lt;/a&gt; for pick intensity for most cities in the world. For times on West coast and more details, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.physlink.com/News/111103LeonidMeteors.cfm&#34; target=&#34;new&#34;&gt;check out this press release&lt;/a&gt;. Just don&amp;rsquo;t expect something like that image of meteor shower on this site!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evanescence @ Webster Hall, NYC</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/evanescence-webster-hall-nyc-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2003 02:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/evanescence-webster-hall-nyc-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://launch.yahoo.com/artist/default.asp?artistID=1098798&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Evanescence&lt;/a&gt; will be performing live at Webster Hall on 16th Sep in New York City as part of their tour. This is little unusual because even the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webster-hall.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Webster Hall&lt;/a&gt; is kind of the top dance club in the City, I never heard any concerts happening there. But probably thats what makes this cool. Check for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nintendofusiontour.com/tour_dates.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tickets and other tour locations&lt;/a&gt;. But beaware, tickets are being distributed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ticketmaster.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the worst ticketing site in the world&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunset And Moonrise</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/sunset-and-moonrise-2003-09-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2003 06:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/sunset-and-moonrise-2003-09-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, Sep 9, Sunset is at 7:16 PM and moonrise is also at 7:16 PM. Cool right? Good way to see this would be at &lt;a href=&#34;http://members.aol.com/visitnj/visitnjhighpoint.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;High Point State Park&lt;/a&gt; or a &lt;a href=&#34;http://newyork.sierraclub.org/outings/Schedules/SepHikes.htm#Sep%206%20%28Sat%29%20FOREST%20RESTORATION%20WORKSHOP%20-%20GRETA%20MOULTON%20TRACT%20AT%20HIGH%20ROCK&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;special hike from Sierra Club&lt;/a&gt;. My preference is former, undoubtably the best place in NJ to see this!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mars Viewing</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/mars-viewing-aug-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2003 06:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/mars-viewing-aug-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just saw the red planet through my 4.5&amp;quot; telescope and 10mm eye piece. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.msnbc.com/news/957424.asp?0cv=CB20&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Unlike it was advertised on several web sites&lt;/a&gt;, no, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get as big as moon when looking through modest telescope. Infect there&amp;rsquo;s barely any difference when I&amp;rsquo;d looked at it through same scope in last couple of years. So I just went in to &lt;a href=&#34;http://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/planetary/factsheet/marsfact.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;some number crunching using fact sheet at Nasa&amp;rsquo;s web site&lt;/a&gt;, and it seems that Mars should look (at best) 30% more brighter and around 40% bigger then I&amp;rsquo;d seen couple of years ago. Now the catch is that when looking through telescope with above spec (which is pretty beyond modest 70mm stuff), Mars would normally look like a bright tiny disk. So 40% increase would make that tiny disk little bigger - but still a tiny. To make it look as big as Moon you would need increment of 1000% or more and that&amp;rsquo;s not going to achievable just by Mars coming closer - it&amp;rsquo;s possible only though much much bigger scopes. So my conclusion is that news sites and emails that kept circulating were pretty misleading to public. Though the good part is that lots of people suddenly got interested in astronomy. Infect one of my friend was so hopeful that he has put a $100 bet with me on whether Mars would look as big as moon on 27th August with bare naked eyes! So I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely disappointed with this hoax, at least someone would get some money :).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astronomy Events This Month</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/astronomy-events-this-month-aug-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2003 06:06:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/astronomy-events-this-month-aug-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mars is going to be the closest to Earth in recorded human history so far. You can go out at midnight and look in the South and the big blob of orangish yellow light (which you might mistake as air plane) is Mars. Even on the rainy nights you can see it lurking behind the cloud - it&amp;rsquo;s that bright. Infect it&amp;rsquo;s brighter then anything after Sun and Moon! Even in a modest telescope you can see it&amp;rsquo;s big bright surface magnified as large as Moon. More info is in &lt;a href=&#34;http://urbanlegends.miningco.com/library/bl_mars_encounter.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this newsletter&lt;/a&gt;. Next Perseid meteor shower peaks on Aug 13, 2003. I&amp;rsquo;d spotted couple of shooting stars last week in just about two hours of time span and thought I was lucky! Well, this was the scientific reason behind it, actually.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T3 On DLP and Matrix II On IMAX</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/t3-on-dlp-and-matrix-ii-on-imax/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2003 05:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/t3-on-dlp-and-matrix-ii-on-imax/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I saw &lt;a href=&#34;http://us.imdb.com/Title?0088247&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Terminator&lt;/a&gt; for the first time few years back, it had struck me like a lightening. Though most people considered it just another action flick, it was one of very few movies which I guess could change lives and sets the directions. And so to the date, it&amp;rsquo;s still my #1 favorite movie. I thought there won&amp;rsquo;t be &lt;a href=&#34;http://us.imdb.com/Title?0181852&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Terminator 3&lt;/a&gt;. When I heard about it, seen previews and learned that director is not James Cameron, my prediction for it was to be a soulless sure flop. Well, I was wrong and right. It is flop and it&amp;rsquo;s sure not as influential as the original. But it&amp;rsquo;s still totally worth watching. It&amp;rsquo;s probably the best action film I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so far. The car chase sequences are anything that you would have seen on the big screen (The car chase in Matrix II now looks like kids play). So it has become one of few movies that I&amp;rsquo;ve went out to see it twice. If it&amp;rsquo;s available in your area, choose the theater with Digital Projection (DLP) for fine DVD-like details on big screen. If you live in NJ, &lt;a href=&#34;http://movies.yahoo.com/showtimes/showtimes.html?t=Loews%20Jersey%20Gardens%20Theatres&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Loews Jersey Gardens Theaters&lt;/a&gt; is the place to go. Next, Matrix Reloaded is released on monster screens of IMAX. This is remastered edition rather then real IMAX movie but it&amp;rsquo;s fun to watch those special effects on 8 story screen :).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jersey Starquest and other star parties</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/jersey-starquest-and-other-star-parties/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2003 17:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/jersey-starquest-and-other-star-parties/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Star parties are event with all night deep sky observations and chance to meet other fellow amateur astronomers. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.princetonastronomy.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;first one of the year at East Coast&lt;/a&gt; is happening this weekend at Hope, NJ. There&amp;rsquo;s usually crowd of 20-30 people with all level of skills. You can try all sorts of telescopes (some as large as 17&amp;quot;) and instruments for deep sky CCD observations and so on. There are going to be day time events, talks and presentations and sun spot watching! If you missed this, there is 3 more popular star parties coming up this year. Check &lt;a href=&#34;http://skyandtelescope.com/resources/calendar/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the event calander at S&amp;amp;T site&lt;/a&gt;. You can see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dotphoto.com/go.asp?l=sytel&amp;amp;AID=421285&amp;amp;Pres=Y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;some photographs I took of last year&amp;rsquo;s star parties&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bolly Flicks On TCM</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/bolly-flicks-on-tcm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2003 19:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/bolly-flicks-on-tcm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.turnerclassicmovies.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Turner&amp;rsquo;s classic movie&lt;/a&gt; channel will be showing three &lt;a href=&#34;http://directory.google.com/Top/Regional/Asia/India/Arts_and_Entertainment/Movies/Hindi/Bollywood/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bollywood movies&lt;/a&gt; in a row on every Thursday starting 8 PM. This is on experimental bases for the month of June. The bollywood movies have an average opinion of being stupid, mostly same, colorful, frequent with dance sequences with no reason and something that makes most females burst out of tears all the time. But the movies that TCM was showing since past few weeks were some of the very best, including my rare personal favorites, that&amp;rsquo;s far away from this average opinion. So I guess it would be worth to check out their schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central Park Summerstage and 311</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/central-park-summerstage-2003-and-311/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2003 20:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/central-park-summerstage-2003-and-311/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Central Park summer stage schedule is out. Mark your dates from their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.summerstage.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;official home page&lt;/a&gt;. On 311, this is a new number you can dial in New York and ask any question or make any complaints - literally! This is due to effort of new mayor Bloomberg to combine several agency to one spot through one number! Want to know how to dispose refrigerator? or complain about that loud car alarm? Dial 311.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jewel Moments</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/jewel-moments-central-park-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2003 15:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/jewel-moments-central-park-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2003/06/jewel_intution.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2003/06/jewel_intution-247x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jewel_intution&#34; width=&#34;247&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; class=&#34;alignleft size-medium wp-image-1111&#34; srcset=&#34;http://shitalshah.com/ShitalShahWP/wp-content/uploads/2003/06/jewel_intution-247x300.jpg 247w, http://shitalshah.com/ShitalShahWP/wp-content/uploads/2003/06/jewel_intution.jpg 413w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 247px) 100vw, 247px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one fine spring morning, a beautiful lady with the sweetest voice decided to walk in a gorgeous park and sing for whoever cared. It was Saturday morning, one of the least busy time of the week when rest of the world prefers to sleep after long Friday night. It was one of the most invisibly promoted concert - even a professional certified guide at Central Park just 200 feet away from the stage didn&amp;rsquo;t knew about it! But still many of us did knew and hassled through early Saturday morning to be there. There were even fans who literally set up their front line spaces before sun came up. Then there was a &amp;ldquo;Jewel stalker&amp;rdquo; who tried a stunt to reach her with roses. Jewel being inherently very shy and sensitive, you don&amp;rsquo;t expect lots of fun fair on the stage. It goes smoothly with occasional emotional bursts until she feels comfortable with the whole thing. And then she can tell jokes and attempt to be funny. She doesn&amp;rsquo;t try to create exact replica of her album versions, instead almost always she would change tempo, tones and add twists. One often discussed disappointment was new hair style (change from the one with &lt;a href=&#34;http://shital.com/images/posts/2003/06/jewel_intution.jpg&#34;&gt;long beautiful hair&lt;/a&gt;). She is sure my #1 favorite female artists and I been envy of people who heard her live when she still a coffee house singer. Her open air concert in the world&amp;rsquo;s greatest city and gorgeous park on that fine spring morning just looked like falling from the heaven. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dotphoto.com/go.asp?l=sytel&amp;amp;AID=810156&amp;amp;Pres=Y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Catch her few glimpse in my photo albums section&lt;/a&gt;. Her new album &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/B00008OWZE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;0304&lt;/a&gt; is already in the stores and I guess she might have &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jeweljk.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;more upcoming events&lt;/a&gt; in case you are interested.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Total Lunar Eclipse (May 15, 2003)</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/total-lunar-eclipse-may-15-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2003 03:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/total-lunar-eclipse-may-15-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Total lunar eclipse coming on 5/15/2003. Most of US can see it. 10:03 PM ET. Awesome sight! Check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://sunearth.gsfc.nasa.gov/eclipse/extra/TLE2003May15.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;press release from NASA&lt;/a&gt; for more info on why this happens and local times in other countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Courtesy: hubble_this text alert list on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freeup.com/&#34;&gt;Verizon mobile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mercury On West</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/mercury-on-west-apr-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2003 16:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/mercury-on-west-apr-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Elusive, offen hiddden planet Mercury is visible this week. In USA, look low and west after sunset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Courtesy: hubble_this text alert list on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freeup.com/&#34;&gt;Verizon mobile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York Shows</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/new-york-shows-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2003 16:13:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/new-york-shows-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are two shows currently on in New York city and it&amp;rsquo;s last week for both (i.e. until 27th April 2003). One of them is International Auto show at 38th street and 11th avenue at Jacob K. Javits Convention Center (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.autoshowny.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://www.autoshowny.com&lt;/a&gt;). You can open the doors of most commercial cars on display and sit in (including Hummer H2) to see how it feels like it. While this might be exciting for some people, I found it more or less boring. It&amp;rsquo;s like walking around a big parking lot. Except few Porches, Ferraris, Bentley and few concept cars everything else you can see on everyday roads in US anyway. The best car I saw was Bufori, a $110,000 machine which has 1930 classic looks from outside and ultra hi-tech from inside. The next event happening in NYC is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.macys.com/campaign/flowershow/newyork/index.jsp?bhcp=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Macy&amp;rsquo;s Flower Show&lt;/a&gt; at Herald Square. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been there but the flyer says over a million flowers, 30,000 species from 6 continents are on display. Spring rulez. Try not to miss it :). Next on the list is Central Park Summerstage. This is a popular summer destination where professional artists performs live and free of charge. This year &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pollstar.com/tour/searchall.pl?By=Artist&amp;amp;Content=JEWEL&amp;amp;PSKey=Y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jewel is going to be there on 10the May&lt;/a&gt;. Jewel is one of my top favorites - probably the best female vocal on the planet. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for her concerts but there weren&amp;rsquo;t any so far and now it&amp;rsquo;s right here in central Park and that too free!! I got this alert from pollstar.com - these guys keeps keeps a watch on concerts and music events - but I can&amp;rsquo;t get additional information or varification for this event.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Picks: Movies, Concerts And Art</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/picks-movies-concerts-and-art-mar-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2003 07:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/picks-movies-concerts-and-art-mar-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three movies that you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t miss this season: 1. Chicago - A total classic. Very different. Nice screen play. Cool lightings and photography. These guys got nominated for 13 acadami awards and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t surprised. 2. About Schmidt - A movie that gonna move you. Shatter you. Only for hard core reality fans. 3. The Guru - A cool hilarious flick on an Indina emigrant. Neat. Concerts: 1. Matchbox Twenty is on roll. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.matchboxtwenty.com/tour.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Click here their schedules&lt;/a&gt; for NY/NJ area. 2. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nowrunning.com/eventsFolder/UnityOfLight/ny.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The unity of light&lt;/a&gt; - A concert by my favorite Indian artist A.R. Raheman. This will feature several other BIG artists from Bollywood music scene. Looks very cool to me. Art: The 50th anniversary of the discovery of the double helix is now being celebrated visually, with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2003/03/14/arts/design/14BOXE.html?th&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;six different exhibitions in Manhattan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Story Reading At Symphony Space</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/story-reading-at-symphony-space-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2003 07:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/story-reading-at-symphony-space-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This one is cool artsy low-profile New York event. Nothing much happens: a celebrity comes on stage and reads you a short story. It&amp;rsquo;s an experience, given the right story teller, how much different a story becomes when someone reads it to you. Visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.symphonyspace.org/genres/seriesPage?seriesId=29&amp;amp;genreId=4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Symphony Space&amp;rsquo;s website&lt;/a&gt; to get more info on shows. I think shows will run through June. My last year&amp;rsquo;s favorite was one called Boys from the Best American Short Stories. This will probably be repeated this year too. But watch out for it, that had been a sold out show last year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shooting Stars Getting Ready To Fall</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/shooting-stars-getting-ready-to-fall-2002/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2002 05:14:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/shooting-stars-getting-ready-to-fall-2002/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Leonid meteor shower is slowing down every year but it&amp;rsquo;s still a magnificent event. I was fortunate to witness this heavenly fireworks last year at a mountain lake some 20 minutes away from my home and there was shooting stars falling down at the rate of one per second for the entire period of more then 15 minutes. Now that&amp;rsquo;s more shooting stars a person would otherwise see in his or her entire life time! Well, I didn&amp;rsquo;t had too many wishes to make so came back home with just memories of bright lines meteors made and their reflections in the lake. This year it&amp;rsquo;s gonna be around 6 times less intense (that is only 10 meteors/min) but still that&amp;rsquo;s a lot! For USA East coast residents the peak will be at 5:30 AM on 19th November (while predicted blue moon is just setting on the west). Check out more info at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.space.com/leonids/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;space.com&lt;/a&gt;. Also, if you had like to be keep up with such time sensitive news, head down to &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/shital/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;my personal group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two IMAX Flicks</title>
      <link>http://shital.com/p/space-station-3d-starwars-epi-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2002 04:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://shital.com/p/space-station-3d-starwars-epi-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just watched new episode of South Park and took my regular dosage of grossness, cursing and offensive language. Feels better&amp;hellip; love it! Ok&amp;hellip; now back to the bad stuff. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been keeping track of new movies since past couple of months because all of them pretty much sucked but now here&amp;rsquo;s two IMAX movies that you might not be aware of and that&amp;rsquo;s gonna go away soon. Both are running at Loews IMAX theater (67th St and Broadway, New York City).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://movies.yahoo.com/shop?d=hv&amp;amp;cf=info&amp;amp;id=1808393554&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Space Station 3D&lt;/a&gt;: This is the movie that you don&amp;rsquo;t want to absolutely miss. Watching this movie on huge 8 story high screen, with 42 speakers and in 3D is probably the next best thing to be actually there in space. It has been shot by actual astronauts with cameras in their helmets. The philosophical thoughts of us being something special is sure to trigger in your mind when you show those awesomely beautiful Earth views filling your entire eye sight on that huge screen. Photography of zero gravity environment, astronauts&amp;rsquo; daily lives and their way of having fun is just amazing. Recommended sit: The very first row!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://movies.yahoo.com/shop?d=hv&amp;amp;cf=info&amp;amp;id=1808439536&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Star Wars - Episode II&lt;/a&gt;: I&amp;rsquo;m not a Star Wars fan but this might be worth to check out if you have extra time and money. I&amp;rsquo;d watched Episode II when it came out earlier this year (it was than running at &lt;a href=&#34;http://movies.yahoo.com/showtimes/showtimes.html?z=10001&amp;amp;r=sim&amp;amp;m=&amp;amp;t=AMC%20Empire%2025&amp;amp;a=&amp;amp;dt=0&amp;amp;s=tm&amp;amp;p=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AMC&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s digital cinema which is probably one of very few of it&amp;rsquo;s kind) but to say the least, it&amp;rsquo;s the weird story even for geeks! The IMAX version is not really re-created for huge screen and you can clearly see the low resolution distortions in graphic effects when it&amp;rsquo;s projected on that huge screen. However that chase scene with sky diving sequences in futuristic city are the real treat and totally worth on the extra large screen. The THX digital sound effect also works great. This movie has limited engagement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
